根据目前所有已知的飞行定律
According to all known laws of aviation,
蜜蜂是不可能飞起来的
there is no way a bee should be able to fly.
它们的翅膀小得根本无法 让胖乎乎的身体离开地面
Its wings are too small to get its fat little body off the ground.
当然，蜜蜂终究还是飞起来了
The bee, of course, flies anyway
因为它们根本不在意那些 在人类看来不可能的事情
because bees don't care what humans think is impossible.
黄配黑、黄配黑、黄配黑、黄配黑
Yellow, black. Yellow, black. Yellow, black. Yellow, black.
哇噢，黑配黄的！换换口味吧
Ooh, black and yellow! Let's shake it up a little.
巴里！吃早饭啦
Barry! Breakfast is ready!
来啦！
Coming!
等下
Hang on a second.
喂？
Hello?
- 巴里？ - 亚当？
- Barry? - Adam?
- 你相信这一刻真的就要到来了么？ - 我也觉得难以置信，待会儿去接你
- Can you believe this is happening? - I can't. I'll pick you up.
“锐”气逼人哈
Looking sharp.
巴里，你怎么不走楼梯呢？ 你爸为了装这个，可是花了好多钱
Use the stairs. Your father paid good money for those.
对不起，我太激动了
Sorry. I'm excited.
大学毕业生在这儿呢，乖儿子 我们都为你骄傲
Here's the graduate. We're very proud of you, son.
完美的成绩单，所有都是B
A perfect report card, all B's.
真让人感到骄傲
Very proud.
老妈！我做了发型
Ma! I got a thing going here.
- 你毛上有点儿东西 - 噢，那是有意做的！
- You got lint on your fuzz. - Ow! That's me!
- 记得向我们招手！我们在第11万8千排 - 走了！
- Wave to us! We'll be in row 118,000. - Bye!
巴里，别在屋子里飞！
Barry, I told you, stop flying in the house!
片名：《蜜蜂电影》
（报纸名为《今日蜂房》，头条为“飞盘击中蜂房”）
- 早啊，亚当 - 早，巴里
- Hey, Adam. - Hey, Barry.
- 你搽了发胶吗？ - 用了一点，特别的日子嘛，终于毕业了
- Is that fuzz gel? - A little. Special day, graduation.
我从未想过我还能熬到毕业
Never thought I'd make it.
是啊，3天小学，3天中学
Three days grade school, three days high school.
那些日子真难熬
Those were awkward.
3天大学，我真庆幸我抽了一天时间 搭便车在蜂房里逛了一下
Three days college. I'm glad I took a day and hitchhiked around the hive.
你回来之后，的确不同了
You did come back different.
- 早，巴里 - 亚蒂 ，留胡子啦？挺帅的
- Hi, Barry. - Artie, growing a mustache? Looks good.
- 你听说弗兰基的事了吗？ - 听说了
- Hear about Frankie? - Yeah.
- 你打算出席他的葬礼吗？ - 没，我才不去呢
- You going to the funeral? - No, I'm not going.
大家都知道叮了人就得死
Everybody knows, sting someone, you die.
我才不会为了一只松鼠去送死 他做事真是不走脑子
Don't waste it on a squirrel. Such a hothead.
我想他只是一时冲动罢了
I guess he could have just gotten out of the way.
我爱死这个多功能游乐园了 每天出了门就可以玩
I love this incorporating an amusement park into our day.
这就是为什么他们说我们不用休息
That's why we don't need vacations.
这么一看…真是壮观啊
Boy, quite a bit of pomp... under the circumstances.
- 亚当，今天我们长大成人了 - 我们成人了！
- Well, Adam, today we are men. - We are!
- 成年蜜蜂 - 阿门！
- Bee-men. - Amen!
哈利路亚
Hallelujah!
同学们、各位老师和尊贵的来宾们
Students, faculty, distinguished bees,
请欢迎巴兹威尔（原文直译为“叫得好”） 院长讲话
please welcome Dean Buzzwell.
欢迎来自新蜂房城
Welcome, New Hive City graduating class of...
9:15班的毕业生
...9:15.
毕业典礼结束了
That concludes our ceremonies.
接着，你们在蜂房工业公司的 职业生涯马上开始！
And begins your career at Honex Industries!
我们今天就要选工作了？
Will we pick ourjob today?
我听说只是先了解一下情况
I heard it's just orientation.
抬起头！出发喽
Heads up! Here we go.
参观期间，请不要将头、手伸出车外
Keep your hands and antennas inside the tram at all times.
（用另一门语言又说了一遍）
- 不知道里面会是怎么样的呢？ - 真有点怕怕
- Wonder what it'll be like? - A little scary.
欢迎来到蜂房工业 它是蜂房控股下属的一个部门
Welcome to Honex, a division of Honesco
同时也是六角集团（蜂房为六角）的一部分
and a part of the Hexagon Group.
要到了！
This is it!
哇
Wow.
我们知道，作为一只蜜蜂
We know that you, as a bee, have worked your whole life
必须将自己的一生奉献给事业
to get to the point where you can work for your whole life.
我们勇敢的授粉大队把花蜜带回蜂巢后 酿蜜的工作就开始了
Honey begins when our valiant Pollen Jocks bring the nectar to the hive.
我们的绝密配方就是
Our top-secret formula
自动色泽修正、气味调整还有气泡充入
is automatically color-corrected, scent-adjusted and bubble-contoured
形成这种有着独特金色光泽的
into this soothing sweet syrup
镇静、香甜的糖浆 也就是你们所熟知的…
with its distinctive golden glow you know as...
蜂蜜！
Honey!
- 那个女孩不赖啊！ - 那是我表妹！
- That girl was hot. - She's my cousin!
- 啊？ - 是啊，我们大家都是表亲嘛
- She is? - Yes, we're all cousins.
- 对，你说得对 - 在蜂房工业，我们致力于
- Right. You're right. - At Honex, we constantly strive
不断改善蜜蜂生活的方方面面
to improve every aspect of bee existence.
这些蜜蜂正在对一种新型头盔进行抗压测试
These bees are stress-testing a new helmet technology.
- 你觉得他表现如何？ - 有待改善
- What do you think he makes? - Not enough.
这是我们的最新开发的生产流程：接蜜
Here we have our latest advancement, the Krelman.
- 那是干什么的？ - 接住倒蜜罐里残留的蜜滴
- What does that do? - Catches that little strand of honey
能为我们节约不少原料
that hangs after you pour it. Saves us millions.
谁都可以干接蜜员这份工作吗？
Can anyone work on the Krelman?
当然可以啦，我们做的大部分工作都很琐碎
Of course. Most bee jobs are small ones. But bees know
但我们清楚：做好每一个细节 就能成就大事业
that every small job, if it's done well, means a lot.
但选择要谨慎
But choose carefully
因为，你选定一行之后，下半辈子就没得改了
because you'll stay in the job you pick for the rest of your life.
同一个工作，干一辈子？我事先怎么不知道？
The same job the rest of your life? I didn't know that.
现在知道也没什么区别
What's the difference?
很高兴告诉大家： 作为一个物种，2700万年来
You'll be happy to know that bees, as a species, haven't had one day off
蜜蜂从未停歇过一天
in 27 million years.
这么说来，我们只能工作到死？
So you'll just work us to death?
当然，我们会尽力做到
We'll sure try.
哇！真是大开眼界了！
Wow! That blew my mind!
“现在知道没有什么区别” 你怎么能说那样的话？
"What's the difference?" How can you say that?
一份工做到死？必须作出这样的选择，多傻
One job forever? That's an insane choice to have to make.
我可是松了一口气 现在我们一生只需要作一次选择
I'm relieved. Now we only have to make one decision in life.
不过，亚当，他们怎么可以不告诉我们呢？
But, Adam, how could they never have told us that?
为什么你总是挑三捡四？我们只是蜜蜂而已 （街边的牌子：“蜜蜂陷入疯狂：猛叮7人随后自尽”）
Why would you question anything? We're bees.
我们是地球上 组织最严密的群体了
We're the most perfectly functioning society on Earth.
难道你从来就没有想过 一切都安排得太好了吗？
You ever think maybe things work a little too well here?
比如呢？举个例子来看看
Like what? Give me one example.
我说不出来，但是你知道我想说什么
I don't know. But you know what I'm talking about.
请无关人员离开大门，皇家采蜜队即将归巢
Please clear the gate. Royal Nectar Force on approach.
等下，看看吧
Wait a second. Check it out.
- 看，是授粉大队！ - 哇哦
- Hey, those are Pollen Jocks! - Wow.
我从来没有在这么近的距离看过他们
I've never seen them this close.
他们知道蜂巢外面是什么样的
They know what it's like outside the hive.
说得是没错，不过，有些没能回来
Yeah, but some don't come back.
- 嘿，勇士们！ - 嗨，英雄们！
- Hey, Jocks! - Hi, Jocks!
（花蜜）
你们真是好样的！
You guys did great!
你们这帮怪物，飞天英雄！ 我爱死你们了！爱死了！
You're monsters! You're sky freaks! I love it! I love it!
- 真想知道他们刚刚去过哪里 - 我也不知道
- I wonder where they were. - I don't know.
他们过着毫无约束的生活
Their day's not planned.
飞到在蜂巢外面大家不知道的地方 做着大家不知道的事情
Outside the hive, flying who knows where, doing who knows what.
你不是想当授粉员就能当的 他们就是为了授粉而生的
You can'tjust decide to be a Pollen Jock. You have to be bred for that.
是啊
Right.
看这些花粉，你和我可能这辈子 都见不到这么多
Look. That's more pollen than you and I will see in a lifetime.
只是身份的象征而已，蜜蜂们太在意身份了
It's just a status symbol. Bees make too much of it.
可能吧，除非你把它们洒在身上 而又正好被姑娘们看见了
Perhaps. Unless you're wearing it and the ladies see you wearing it.
那些姑娘？她们不也是我们的表亲吗？
Those ladies? Aren't they our cousins too?
远亲，远亲
Distant. Distant.
看看他俩
Look at these two.
- 两个小淘气鬼罢了 - 逗逗他们去
- Couple of Hive Harrys. - Let's have fun with them.
当授粉员一定很危险吧
It must be dangerous being a Pollen Jock.
可不是！有一次，一只熊把我按在蘑菇上！
Yeah. Once a bear pinned me against a mushroom!
他一爪掐着我的喉咙，另一只爪来扇我耳光！ 左-右-开-弓
He had a paw on my throat, and with the other, he was slapping me!
- 天哪！ - 我从没有想过打倒他
- Oh, my! - I never thought I'd knock him out.
你当时在干什么？
What were you doing during this?
当然是一直尽力向总部发出警报啦
Trying to alert the authorities.
我可以给你签个名
I can autograph that.
今天外面有点大风哦，是不是啊，小兄弟？
A little gusty out there today, wasn't it, comrades?
是啊，起风了
Yeah. Gusty.
我们计划明天去离蜂房大概六里地的 向日葵地采蜜
We're hitting a sunflower patch six miles from here tomorrow.
- 六里是吧？ - 巴里！
- Six miles, huh? - Barry!
对我们来说，就像跳过一个水潭那么简单 但你们可能就不行
A puddle jump for us, but maybe you're not up for it.
- 也许我行 - 别逞强！
- Maybe I am. - You are not!
明天0900从J号门出发 （0900：表示9点，如15点为1500）
We're going 0900 at J-Gate.
小鬼头，怎么样？你够胆来吗？
What do you think, buzzy-boy? Are you bee enough?
只要知道0900是什么意思，我就够胆去
I might be. It all depends on what 0900 means.
哟，要上班啦！
Hey, Honex!
老爸，吓我一跳
Dad, you surprised me.
你想好对什么感兴趣了吗？
You decide what you're interested in?
- 呃，有太多选择了 - 但你只能挑一个
- Well, there's a lot of choices. - But you only get one.
老爸，你有没有觉得每天重复同样的工作很无聊？
Do you ever get bored doing the same job every day?
乖儿子，我来跟你说说搅拌工作是怎样的
Son, let me tell you about stirring.
你抓起搅拌棍，一圈一圈地搅啊搅啊
You grab that stick, and you just move it around, and you stir it around.
你会找到一种节奏，那感觉美妙极了
You get yourself into a rhythm. It's a beautiful thing.
爸，你知道吗？
You know, Dad, the more I think about it,
我越想越觉得，我不适合呆在酿蜜车间里
maybe the honey field just isn't right for me.
那你想干什么？ 每天气鼓鼓地怨天尤人？
You were thinking of what, making balloon animals?
对搅拌工来说，那可是不称职的
That's a bad job for a guy with a stinger.
珍妮特，你的宝贝儿子还不知道 要不要去酿蜜呢！
Janet, your son's not sure he wants to go into honey!
- 巴里，有时候你真逗 - 我可不是在开玩笑
- Barry, you are so funny sometimes. - I'm not trying to be funny.
你当然不是在开玩笑，你要去酿蜜 我们的儿子，当然是搅拌工！
You're not funny! You're going into honey. Our son, the stirrer!
- 你要做搅拌工？ - 你们都没有听我讲话啊！
- You're gonna be a stirrer? - No one's listening to me!
等你看到我用的那些棍子就不会这样了
Wait till you see the sticks I have.
我现在说什么都无所谓了 我要刺一个蚂图案的纹身
I could say anything right now. I'm gonna get an ant tattoo!
咱们开些新鲜蜂蜜来庆祝一下吧！
Let's open some honey and celebrate!
我要在喉咙上穿个孔，再刮一下触角
Maybe I'll pierce my thorax. Shave my antennae.
和蚱蜢同居，镶金牙，见人就叫“狗”！
Shack up with a grasshopper. Get a gold tooth and call everybody "dawg"!
我真感到自豪
I'm so proud.
- 我真不相信，我们今天就要开始工作了 - 今天是个大日子啊
- We're starting work today! - Today's the day.
快点！好工作都被人抢走了！
Come on! All the good jobs will be gone.
对，没错
Yeah, right.
（工作安排板 职位名称 总数 空余 状态 优先级） 花粉计数员、特技工、倒蜜工、搅拌工 前台接待、毛发清洁工…
Pollen counting, stunt bee, pouring, stirrer, front desk, hair removal...
- 这个工作还要人吗？ - 等我查下，还有两个空位！
- Is it still available? - Hang on. Two left!
（除垢工） 其中一个位子是你的了！恭喜！站到这边来
One of them's yours! Congratulations! Step to the side.
- 你找到什么工作？ - 除垢工，真棒！
- What'd you get? - Picking crud out. Stellar!
哇！
Wow!
两个新人？
Couple of newbies?
没错！第一天，我们已经准备好了！
Yes, sir! Our first day! We are ready!
上前来，选一份吧
Make your choice.
- 你想先来吗？ - 不，你先来
- You want to go first? - No, you go.
天哪，哪些还有空位呢？
Oh, my. What's available?
厕所清洁工，但不是你想的那样
Restroom attendant's open, not for the reason you think.
- 可不可以做接蜜工？ - 当然可以，这是你的了
- Any chance of getting the Krelman? - Sure, you're on.
抱歉，职位刚好满人
I'm sorry, the Krelman just closed out.
上蜡员总是缺人
Wax monkey's always open.
接蜜员又缺人了
The Krelman opened up again.
怎么回事啊？
What happened?
一只蜜蜂死了，就空出一个位子，懂吗？ 一只死了，另一只又死了
A bee died. Makes an opening. See? He's dead. Another dead one.
死啦，死啦，然后又有两只死了
Deady. Deadified. Two more dead.
站着死，倒着死，这就是命！
Dead from the neck up. Dead from the neck down. That's life!
哦，真是难选！
Oh, this is so hard!
加热工、冷却工、特技工 倒蜜工、搅拌工
Heating, cooling, stunt bee, pourer, stirrer,
泡沫工、7号监督员、纱布协调员 条纹制服供应员、幼虫饲养员
humming, inspector number seven, lint coordinator, stripe supervisor,
巴里，你觉得我该选…巴里？
mite wrangler. Barry, what do you think I should... Barry?
巴里！
Barry!
各单位注意，我们要到向日葵田采蜜 就在在蜂房第9象限…
All right, we've got the sunflower patch in quadrant nine...
你是怎么回事啊？你跑哪去了？
What happened to you? Where are you?
- 我要出去 - 出去？出哪去？
- I'm going out. - Out? Out where?
- 出外面去 - 噢，千万不要去！
- Out there. - Oh, no!
在我开始一辈子的工作之前 我必须去外面见识一下
I have to, before I go to work for the rest of my life.
你会死的！你疯了！喂？
You're gonna die! You're crazy! Hello?
有电话打进来了
Another call coming in.
如果谁今天觉得自己特别神勇
If anyone's feeling brave, there's a Korean deli on 83rd
就去采83路的韩国熟食店外的玫瑰花
that gets their roses today.
伙计们好
Hey, guys.
- 看看那边 - 你不是我们昨天见到的小孩吗？
- Look at that. - Isn't that the kid we saw yesterday?
站住，小鬼 起飞台严禁出入
Hold it, son, flight deck's restricted.
没关系，卢，我们把他带上
It's OK, Lou. We're gonna take him up.
是吗？你今天真是好运
Really? Feeling lucky, are you?
在这里，还有这里签上名，这里写首字母就行
Sign here, here. Just initial that.
- 谢谢 - 好
- Thank you. - OK.
今天有下雨警报
You got a rain advisory today,
大家都知道，蜜蜂是不可以在雨中飞行的
and as you all know, bees cannot fly in rain.
所以像往常一样，大家都要小心
So be careful. As always, watch your brooms,
小心扫把、球棒、狗、小鸟、熊和蝙蝠
hockey sticks, dogs, birds, bears and bats.
同时，我收到两份报告说 我们的同伴被根汁汽水淋湿了 （美国一种无酒精饮料）
Also, I got a couple of reports of root beer being poured on us.
墨菲就因为那玩意儿还在家休养呢 像蝉一样唠叨个不停
Murphy's in a home because of it, babbling like a cicada!
- 真是糟糕 - 尤其是你，新丁，我提醒你
- That's awful. - And a reminder for you rookies,
蜜蜂法律第一条：绝对不允许和人类说话！
bee law number one, absolutely no talking to humans!
好，排好起飞队形
All right, launch positions!
嘿哟嗬，嗨哟嗬…
Buzz, buzz, buzz, buzz! Buzz, buzz, buzz, buzz! Buzz, buzz, buzz, buzz!
黄黑战士们！
Black and yellow!
到！
Hello!
准备好了吗？要出发了
You ready for this, hot shot?
准备好了，放马过来吧
Yeah. Yeah, bring it on.
风向检查，完毕
Wind, check.
- 天线检查，完毕 - 花蜜收集器检查，完毕
- Antennae, check. - Nectar pack, check.
- 翅膀检查，完毕 - 锋针检查，完毕
- Wings, check. - Stinger, check.
恐惧程度检查，完毕！
Scared out of my shorts, check.
好了，女士们
OK, ladies,
准备出发了！
let's move it out!
勇士们，奋力冲向那些花儿吧！
Pound those petunias, you striped stem-suckers!
把花蜜吸干！
All of you, drain those flowers!
哇，我出来了！
Wow! I'm out!
哇，我出来了！真是难以置信，我出来了
I can't believe I'm out!
天那么蓝
So blue.
飞翔是如此迅速和自由！
I feel so fast and free!
盒形风筝！
Box kite!
哇！
Wow!
花儿们！
Flowers!
我是蓝队长机，发现玫瑰花
This is Blue Leader. We have roses visual.
向下30度俯冲，旋转下降
Bring it around 30 degrees and hold.
玫瑰花！
Roses!
30度，收到 旋转下降
30 degrees, roger. Bringing it around.
站到一边去，小鬼，可能会弹到你
Stand to the side, kid. It's got a bit of a kick.
这只用一个花蜜收集器！
That is one nectar collector!
- 没这么近地见过授粉吧？ - 没有
- Ever see pollination up close? - No, sir.
我在这里捡一点花粉 这里撒一点，那边撒一点
I pick up some pollen here, sprinkle it over here. Maybe a dash over there,
在那朵花上撒一点，看到了吗？ 有点像玩魔术游戏一样
a pinch on that one. See that? It's a little bit of magic.
真是神奇，为什么要这样做呢？
That's amazing. Why do we do that?
因为花粉越多，花开得越盛 就越多花蜜，酿出来的蜂蜜就越多
That's pollen power. More pollen, more flowers, more nectar, more honey for us.
好厉害啊
Cool.
我发现有很多鲜黄色点，有可能是雏菊 我们要去吗？
I'm picking up a lot of bright yellow. Could be daisies. Don't we need those?
图像收到
Copy that visual.
等下，其中一朵花好像在动
Wait. One of these flowers seems to be on the move.
再说一遍？你发现了正在移动的花？
Say again? You're reporting a moving flower?
没错
Affirmative.
是压线球！
That was on the line!
帅呆了，这是什么呀？
This is the coolest. What is it?
不知道啊，不过我很喜欢这个颜色
I don't know, but I'm loving this color.
很好闻，虽然不像是花，但我喜欢
It smells good. Not like a flower, but I like it.
毛茸茸的
Yeah, fuzzy.
有点化学味道
Chemical-y.
小心点，伙计，有点粘
Careful, guys. It's a little grabby.
我的上帝啊！
My sweet lord of bees!
傻小子，快下来！
Candy-brain, get off there!
麻烦来了！
Problem!
- 伙计们！ - 这可会出事哦
- Guys! - This could be bad.
完全赞成
Affirmative.
好险
Very close.
差点弄伤
Gonna hurt.
我的妈呀
Mama's little boy.
你站错地方了，新丁！
You are way out of position, rookie!
让我回敬你一球厉害的！
Coming in at you like a missile!
救-命-啊！
Help me!
我觉得这些不是花
I don't think these are flowers.
- 要告诉他吗？ - 我觉得，他应该知道
- Should we tell him? - I think he knows.
这是什么来的呀？！
What is this?!
赛点
Match point!
亲爱的，你可以开始收拾包袱走人了 因为，你这样是自讨苦吃！
You can start packing up, honey, because you're about to eat it!
怎么回事啊！
Yowser!
噢，真恶心
Gross.
车里有只蜜蜂！
There's a bee in the car!
- 想想办法！ - 我正在开车
- Do something! - I'm driving!
- 小蜜蜂，你好
- Hi, bee. - He's back here!
它会蜇我的！
He's going to sting me!
都别动，你不动，它就不蜇你 别动！
Nobody move. If you don't move, he won't sting you. Freeze!
它眨眼了
He blinked!
喷他，奶奶！
Spray him, Granny!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?!
哇，外面真是刺激得难以置信
Wow... the tension level out here is unbelievable.
我要回家了
I gotta get home.
不可以在雨中飞行
Can't fly in rain.
呼救！呼救！正在下降！
Mayday! Mayday! Bee going down!
肯，麻烦你关一下窗
Ken, could you close the window please?
看看我新做的简历，我把它做成了翻折的小册子
Check out my new resume. I made it into a fold-out brochure.
看到了吗？可翻折的
You see? Folds out.
糟糕了，人越来越多，我可不想这样
Oh, no. More humans. I don't need this.
那是什么？
What was that?
也许这次可以，试一次，再试一次…
Maybe this time. This time. This time. This time! This time! This...
封住了！
Drapes!
真糟糕
That is diabolical.
真完美，我写上了所有的特殊技能 甚至我最喜欢的前十部电影
It's fantastic. It's got all my special skills, even my top-ten favorite movies.
最喜欢哪部？星球大战？
What's number one? Star Wars?
我对那些…
Nah, I don't go for that...
东西不太特别感兴趣
...kind of stuff.
难怪我们不可以和他们说话，他们都是疯子
No wonder we shouldn't talk to them. They're out of their minds.
我面试完的时候 他们都大吃一惊，不信我说的话
When I leave a job interview, they're flabbergasted, can't believe what I say.
那里有太阳，也许可以出去
There's the sun. Maybe that's a way out.
我记得太阳上没有写着大大的“75”
I don't remember the sun having a big 75 on it.
我跟你说，我预见到了全球变暖
I predicted global warming.
我觉得越来越热，起初，我以为只有我这样
I could feel it getting hotter. At first I thought it was just me.
等下！住手！有蜜蜂！
Wait! Stop! Bee!
退后，用冬装靴子来打
Stand back. These are winter boots.
住手！
Wait!
不要伤害它！
Don't kill him!
你知道我对蜜蜂过敏！ 我会死的
You know I'm allergic to them! This thing could kill me!
为什么觉得它条命比你的贱？
Why does his life have less value than yours?
为什么觉得它的命比你们的贱？ 这是你说的吗？
Why does his life have any less value than mine? Is that your statement?
我只是说所有生命都有它们的价值 你不了解它们也有思想感情
I'm just saying all life has value. You don't know what he's capable of feeling.
我的简历！
My brochure!
走吧，小家伙
There you go, little guy.
我才不怕它呢，我只是对它过敏
I'm not scared of him. It's an allergic thing.
为什么你不在简历上注明呢？
Put that on your resume brochure.
不是开玩笑的 我整张脸都会肿起来
My whole face could puff up.
把它写成是你的特长
Make it one of your special skills.
打人也是我的特长
Knocking someone out is also a special skill.
就这样，再见，维纳莎，谢谢
Right. Bye, Vanessa. Thanks.
- 维纳莎，“酸奶之夜”就定在下周？ - 好的，肯，什么时候都行
- Vanessa, next week? Yogurt night? - Sure, Ken. You know, whatever.
- 你可以放点炸豆片在上面 - 再见
- You could put carob chips on there. - Bye.
- 我希望少点热量 - 再见
- Supposed to be less calories. - Bye.
我要对她说点什么
I gotta say something.
她救了我一命，我得对她说点什么
She saved my life. I gotta say something.
好，去就去
All right, here it goes.
假的
Nah.
我要说什么呢？
What would I say?
我可能真的会惹来麻烦
I could really get in trouble.
蜜蜂法律规定 不可以和人类说话
It's a bee law. You're not supposed to talk to a human.
我真不相信我要这样做
I can't believe I'm doing this.
我一定要说
I've got to.
我不可以这样做，别这样！
Oh, I can't do it. Come on!
不说，说，不说
No. Yes. No.
说吧，不行
Do it. I can't.
我怎么开头呢？“你喜欢爵士乐吗？”不，没用
How should I start it? "You like jazz?" No, that's no good.
她来了，说啊，你这笨蛋！
Here she comes! Speak, you fool!
你好！
Hi!
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 是你在说话吗？ - 是我
- You're talking. - Yes, I know.
你说话了！
You're talking!
很抱歉，非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
不，没关系，我知道我在发梦
No, it's OK. It's fine. I know I'm dreaming.
但是我不记得我睡下了呀
But I don't recall going to bed.
我知道一定会吓着你
Well, I'm sure this is very disconcerting.
只是有点惊讶，我的意思是说，蜜蜂说话了！
This is a bit of a surprise to me. I mean, you're a bee!
没错，我本不该说话的
I am. And I'm not supposed to be doing this,
但是，如果不是你…
but they were all trying to kill me.
他们都想弄死我
And if it wasn't for you...
我必须谢谢你，这是爸妈教我的
I had to thank you. It's just how I was raised.
真有点怪
That was a little weird.
- 我和一只蜜蜂在说话 - 没错
- I'm talking with a bee. - Yeah.
我对一只蜜蜂说话，蜜蜂也对我说话！
I'm talking to a bee. And the bee is talking to me!
我只是想对你说，我很感激你 我走了
I just want to say I'm grateful. I'll leave now.
- 等下！你怎么学会说话的？ - 学什么？
- Wait! How did you learn to do that? - What?
学讲话
The talking thing.
我猜，和你一样 “妈妈、爸爸、亲爱的”自然就学会了
Same way you did, I guess. "Mama, Dada, honey." You pick it up.
- 真逗 - 就这样
- That's very funny. - Yeah.
蜜蜂都很风趣幽默的 如果我们不笑，就要哭着面对
Bees are funny. If we didn't laugh, we'd cry with what we have to deal with.
笑哭都一样
Anyway...
你要点…
Can I...
- 什么吗？ - 比如？
...get you something? - Like what?
我也不知道，我是说… 我不知道，比如咖啡？
I don't know. I mean... I don't know. Coffee?
我无意冒犯
I don't want to put you out.
不会很麻烦的，就几分钟的功夫
It's no trouble. It takes two minutes.
- 喝杯咖啡而已 - 我不想强迫你
- It's just coffee. - I hate to impose.
- 别傻了 - 实际上，我还真想来一杯
- Don't be ridiculous! - Actually, I would love a cup.
你要吃糖酒蛋糕吗？
Hey, you want rum cake?
- 不用了 - 吃点吧
- I shouldn't. - Have some.
- 不，我不要 - 吃点吧
- No, I can't. - Come on!
我正想在这里减去几毫克
I'm trying to lose a couple micrograms.
- 哪里？ - 这些条纹不会显瘦的
- Where? - These stripes don't help.
你一点都不胖！
You look great!
我觉得你不了解时尚
I don't know if you know anything about fashion.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
没事
No.
他们飞上去麦迪逊的时候 他正在出租车里弄轮胎
He's making the tie in the cab as they're flying up Madison.
最后他终于到了那里
He finally gets there.
他从楼梯冲进教堂里 婚礼正在进行
He runs up the steps into the church. The wedding is on.
然后他说，西瓜呢？ 我以为你在说“门瓜”
And he says, "Watermelon? I thought you said Guatemalan.
我为什么要嫁给一个“西瓜”？
Why would I marry a watermelon?"
这是蜜蜂之间流传的笑话吗？
Is that a bee joke?
差不多就这样吧
That's the kind of stuff we do.
对啊，很不同
Yeah, different.
那么，你打算怎么办，巴里？
So, what are you gonna do, Barry?
工作的事情？我不知道
About work? I don't know.
我想为蜂巢尽我的责任 但是不想按照他们想要的方式
I want to do my part for the hive, but I can't do it the way they want.
我理解你的感受
I know how you feel.
- 真的？ - 当然
- You do? - Sure.
我父母希望我成为一名律师或者医生 但是我想做花商
My parents wanted me to be a lawyer or a doctor, but I wanted to be a florist.
- 真的？ - 我唯一的爱好就是种花
- Really? - My only interest is flowers.
我们新的蜂后就是用相同的口号竞选成功的
Our new queen was just elected with that same campaign slogan.
如果你可以看到
Anyway, if you look...
我的蜂房就在那里，看到了吗？
There's my hive right there. See it?
你们住在绵羊草地上！
You're in Sheep Meadow!
没错，我们就在乌龟池的边上！
Yes! I'm right off the Turtle Pond!
不可能！我去过那个地方 有一次，我就在那里掉了一个趾环
No way! I know that area. I lost a toe ring there once.
- 为什么女生要在脚趾上戴环？ - 为什么不可以？
- Why do girls put rings on their toes? - Why not?
- 就像在你的膝盖上戴帽子一样 - 我会试试看
- It's like putting a hat on your knee. - Maybe I'll try that.
- 你没事吧，小姐？ - 没事，我很好
- You all right, ma'am? - Oh, yeah. Fine.
就是喝两杯咖啡而已！
Just having two cups of coffee!
好了，真的很开心，谢谢你请我喝咖啡
Anyway, this has been great. Thanks for the coffee.
不客气
Yeah, it's no trouble.
抱歉我喝不完了，如果我喝完了，也得撑死了
Sorry I couldn't finish it. If I did, I'd be up the rest of my life.
你可以…
Are you?
我可以带一块走吗？
Can I take a piece of this with me?
当然可以啦！给，带点回去
Sure! Here, have a crumb.
- 谢谢！ - 嗯
- Thanks! - Yeah.
好吧，呃，那么… 我想，我们会再见
All right. Well, then... I guess I'll see you around.
或者不再见
Or not.
没关系，巴里
OK, Barry.
再次多谢你…之前救了我
And thank you so much again... for before.
那件事啊？没什么
Oh, that? That was nothing.
呃，不是“没什么”，但是，不管怎样…
Well, not nothing, but... Anyway...
（测试进行中 飓风生存测试）
这是不可能成功的
This can't possibly work.
他已经准备好了，我们还是试一下吧
He's all set to go. We may as well try it.
好吧，戴维，拉降落伞
OK, Dave, pull the chute.
- 听起来真厉害 - 是很厉害
- Sounds amazing. - It was amazing!
那是我一生中最恐怖又最快乐的时刻
It was the scariest, happiest moment of my life.
人类耶！我真不相信你和人类在一起
Humans! I can't believe you were with humans!
巨型、可怕的人类！他们是怎么样的？
Giant, scary humans! What were they like?
又大又笨，他们说话疯疯癫癫的
Huge and crazy. They talk crazy.
他们吃很大的东西，开车很疯
They eat crazy giant things. They drive crazy.
- 他们有没有像电视里演的那样，想弄死你？ - 有些会，但是有些不会
- Do they try and kill you, like on TV? - Some of them. But some of them don't.
- 你怎么回来的？ - 跟着别人
- How'd you get back? - Poodle.
你成功了，我很高兴 而且你看到你想看到的
You did it, and I'm glad. You saw whatever you wanted to see.
你已经“经历”过了，现在，你回来了 你可以选一份工，过正常生活了
You had your "experience." Now you can pick out yourjob and be normal.
- 就是有点… - 有点？
- Well... - Well?
就是，我遇到了一个人
Well, I met someone.
真的？她是雌蜂？
You did? Was she Bee-ish?
- 不是黄蜂吧？！你父母会宰了你的！ - 不是，不是，不是黄蜂
- A wasp?! Your parents will kill you! - No, no, no, not a wasp.
- 蜘蛛？ - 你知道我不喜欢蜘蛛
- Spider? - I'm not attracted to spiders.
其他人都喜欢八条腿的动物 觉得他们最性感
I know it's the hottest thing, with the eight legs and all.
我都不敢看那张脸
I can't get by that face.
那么她是谁？
So who is she?
她…她是…人类
She's... human.
不会吧，你该不会违反了蜜蜂法吧？
No, no. That's a bee law. You wouldn't break a bee law.
- 她叫维纳莎 - 天啊
- Her name's Vanessa. - Oh, boy.
她很善良，她是一个花商
She's so nice. And she's a florist!
不会吧！你和一个人类花商约会
Oh, no! You're dating a human florist!
我们不是约会
We're not dating.
你飞出了蜂房，和攻击我们的人类说话
You're flying outside the hive, talking to humans that attack our homes
他们用强力清洁剂、“M-80s”炸药 和八分长的雷管来摧毁我们的家园
with power washers and M-80s! One-eighth a stick of dynamite!
她救了我一命，而且，她了解我
She saved my life! And she understands me.
这事到此为止！
This is over!
尝尝这个
Eat this.
这事还没完！那是什么？
This is not over! What was that?
- 他们叫这“碎屑” - 如此刺激和美妙
- They call it a crumb. - It was so stingin' stripey!
这不是他们吃的东西 这只是从他们吃的东西上面掉下来的！
And that's not what they eat. That's what falls off what they eat!
- 你知道什么是肉桂卷吗？ - 不知道
- You know what a Cinnabon is? - No.
- 原料有面包、肉桂还有糖衣，加热… - 小点儿声
It's bread and cinnamon and frosting. They heat it up...
坐下！
Sit down!
…很热！ -听我说！
...really hot! - Listen to me!
我们和他们不一样！我们就是我们 我们有我们生活的空间，他们也是
We are not them! We're us. There's us and there's them!
没错，但是谁能否认心的向往？
Yes, but who can deny the heart that is yearning?
没有什么向往，停止向往，听我说！
There's no yearning. Stop yearning. Listen to me!
你要以认识到我们是蜜蜂，伙计 我们是蜜蜂！
You have got to start thinking bee, my friend. Thinking bee!
- 我们是蜜蜂 - 我们是蜜蜂
- Thinking bee. - Thinking bee.
我们是蜜蜂！我们是蜜蜂！ 我们是蜜蜂！我们是蜜蜂！
Thinking bee! Thinking bee! Thinking bee! Thinking bee!
他在那儿呢，游泳池里
There he is. He's in the pool.
你知道你的问题出在哪儿吗，巴里？
You know what your problem is, Barry?
我要用蜜蜂思维来思考？
I gotta start thinking bee?
你还要消沉多久？
How much longer will this go on?
已经3天了！我搞不懂你为什么不去工作？
It's been three days! Why aren't you working?
我有很多人生的重大问题需要考虑
I've got a lot of big life decisions to think about.
什么人生？你没有人生！ 你没有工作，连只蜜蜂都算不上！
What life? You have no life! You have no job. You're barely a bee!
酿一点儿蜜会要了你的命吗？
Would it kill you to make a little honey?
巴里，上来，你爸在跟你说话呢
Barry, come out. Your father's talking to you.
马丁，你可以跟他谈谈吗？
Martin, would you talk to him?
巴里， 我在和你说话呢！
Barry, I'm talking to you!
你来吗？
You coming?
都准备好了吗？
Got everything?
一切准备就绪！
All set!
你先走，我会追上来的
Go ahead. I'll catch up.
不要太久哦
Don't be too long.
看我的！
Watch this!
维纳莎！
Vanessa!
- 我们还没走呢，巴里 - 我告诉你不要对他嚷嚷
- We're still here. - I told you not to yell at him.
你对他嚷嚷，他就不理你
He doesn't respond to yelling!
- 那你为什么对我嚷嚷呢？ - 因为你不听我说
- Then why yell at me? - Because you don't listen!
我才不听这个
I'm not listening to this.
对不起，我要走了
Sorry, I've gotta go.
- 你去哪？ - 没啥，去见一个朋友
- Where are you going? - I'm meeting a friend.
女孩？所以你才无法作出决定？
A girl? Is this why you can't decide?
再见
Bye.
希望她最好是蜂类的
I just hope she's Bee-ish.
（维纳莎花店）
每年在帕萨迪纳（加州一城市）都有 大型的花车巡游？
They have a huge parade of flowers every year in Pasadena?
能够参加玫瑰展示锦标赛是每个花商的梦想
To be in the Tournament of Roses, that's every florist's dream!
站在在花车上，被鲜花和群众的欢呼所包围
Up on a float, surrounded by flowers, crowds cheering.
锦标赛，是玫瑰花们互相之间比赛吗？
A tournament. Do the roses compete in athletic events?
不是，嗯，我就得到过一次机会 为什么你坐着不飞呢？
No. All right, I've got one. How come you don't fly everywhere?
太累了，你去别的地方为什么不用跑呢？ 那样不是快点吗？
It's exhausting. Why don't you run everywhere? It's faster.
好了，好了，我知道了，该你问了
Yeah, OK, I see, I see. All right, your turn.
“替你录”（TiVo，一种录像机）是怎么回事 你们可以让电视直播停下来吗？真是太夸张了！
TiVo. You can just freeze live TV? That's insane!
你没有见过类似的吗？
You don't have that?
我们有“海沃（Hivo）”，但那是一种病毒 一种很恐怖、很恐怖的病毒
We have Hivo, but it's a disease. It's a horrible, horrible disease.
天啊
Oh, my.
傻蜜蜂！
Dumb bees!
你一定很想蜇死那些混蛋
You must want to sting all those jerks.
我们会克制自己，通常蜇了他们 我们自己也会有生命危险
We try not to sting. It's usually fatal for us.
这么说你很注意控制自己的脾气喽
So you have to watch your temper.
是啊，非常注意：通过踢墙、散步 写泄愤信然后扔掉
Very carefully. You kick a wall, take a walk,
种种手段来发泄那些情绪
write an angry letter and throw it out. Work through it like any emotion:
比如：愤怒、嫉妒或贪婪
Anger, jealousy, lust.
天哪！你没事吧？
Oh, my goodness! Are you OK?
没事
Yeah.
- 怎么回事啊，你！ - 是只小虫子
- What is wrong with you?! - It's a bug.
他又没有影响到别人，滚开，你这讨厌鬼！
He's not bothering anybody. Get out of here, you creep!
那是什么？是《矛与救》的宣传册吗？
What was that? A Pic 'N' Save circular?
是啊，你怎么知道？
Yeah, it was. How did you know?
感觉有10页，75页的话，我们差不多就死定了
It felt like about 10 pages. Seventy-five is pretty much our limit.
你知道得不少
You've really got that down to a science.
- 我有个表亲就被《意大利时尚》打死了 - 不会吧
- I lost a cousin to Italian Vogue. - I'll bet.
这些叫“强大的拉克勒斯”的是什么？
What in the name of Mighty Hercules is this?
这些怎么来的？“爱蜂”，“金色绽放”
How did this get here? Cute Bee, Golden Blossom,
“雷・利奥塔（好莱坞影星）的私人收藏”？
Ray Liotta Private Select?
- 他就是那个演员吗？ - 我从来没有听说过
- Is he that actor? - I never heard of him.
- 这些怎么会在这里？ - 卖给人们吃啊
- Why is this here? - For people. We eat it.
为什么？你们吃的东西还不够多吗？
You don't have enough food of your own?
- 嗯，是的 - 你们怎么弄到这些蜂蜜的？
- Well, yes. - How do you get it?
- 蜜蜂酿造的 - 我知道是谁酿的！
- Bees make it. - I know who makes it!
我还知道酿造过程很不容易呢！
And it's hard to make it!
要加热、冷却、搅拌，还要接蜜 一点都不能浪费
There's heating, cooling, stirring. You need a whole Krelman thing!
- 那是有机物 - 那是“我”机物！
- It's organic. - It's our-ganic!
蜂蜜而已啊，巴里
It's just honey, Barry.
什么，“而已”？
Just what?!
蜜蜂们都不知道这件事！这是偷窃！ 很严重的偷窃！
Bees don't know about this! This is stealing! A lot of stealing!
你们已经夺走了我们的家、学校和医院 这是我们唯一剩下的了
You've taken our homes, schools, hospitals! This is all we have!
还要半价出售？我一定要调查到底
And it's on sale?! I'm getting to the bottom of this.
我一定要把事情查个水落石出！
I'm getting to the bottom of all of this!
嗨，赫克托
Hey, Hector.
- 快搞定了吗？ - 差不多了
- You almost done? - Almost.
它在这儿，我能感觉到
He is here. I sense it.
好了，我该回家了
Well, I guess I'll go home now
把这香甜的蜂蜜留在空无一人的仓库里
and just leave this nice honey out, with no one around.
人赃并获，小偷！
You're busted, box boy!
我就听到有声音，原来你会说话！
I knew I heard something. So you can talk!
没错，现在该你说了
I can talk. And now you'll start talking!
你从哪儿弄来这些蜂蜜的？谁是你的供货商？
Where you getting the sweet stuff? Who's your supplier?
我听不懂你在说什么，我觉得我们是朋友
I don't understand. I thought we were friends.
我最讨厌让朋友（指蜜蜂）伤心了！
The last thing we want to do is upset bees!
你来晚了！蜂蜜现在是我们的了！
You're too late! It's ours now!
先生，你，找错对手了！
You, sir, have crossed the wrong sword!
先生，你，将会成为我养的大蜥蜴的午餐！
You, sir, will be lunch for my iguana, Ignacio!
蜂蜜从哪里来的？
Where is the honey coming from?
哪里来的？
Tell me where!
“蜂蜜农庄”！从“蜂蜜农庄”来！
Honey Farms! It comes from Honey Farms!
疯子！
Crazy person!
这里发生了什么悲剧吗？
What horrible thing has happened here?
看看这些脸，他们都不知道这是怎么一回事
These faces, they never knew what hit them. And now
现在又要去一个不知名的地方
they're on the road to nowhere!
别动
Just keep still.
什么？你还没有死？
What? You're not dead?
我看起来像死了吗？他们会把会动的都扫走 你去哪儿？
Do I look dead? They will wipe anything that moves. Where you headed?
养蜂场，我有重任在身
To Honey Farms. I am onto something huge here.
我要去阿拉斯加，喝驼鹿血，美味啊，棒极了！
I'm going to Alaska. Moose blood, crazy stuff. Blows your head off!
我要去塔科马港
I'm going to Tacoma.
- 那你呢？ - 他是真死了
- And you? - He really is dead.
那算了
All right.
大事不好！
Uh-oh!
- 那是什么？ - 不要！
- What is that?! - Oh, no!
- 雨刷器！三层刀刃的！ - 三层刀刃？
- A wiper! Triple blade! - Triple blade?
跳上来！这是你唯一的机会，蜜蜂小弟！
Jump on! It's your only chance, bee!
为什么所有东西都要那么干净？
Why does everything have to be so doggone clean?!
你们人类看多少是多啊？！
How much do you people need to see?!
睁大双眼！ 把头伸出窗外！
Open your eyes! Stick your head out the window!
全国公共广播，我是卡尔・卡塞尔 以下是来自华盛顿的消息
From NPR News in Washington, I'm Carl Kasell.
不要再残杀生灵了！
But don't kill no more bugs!
- 蜜蜂小弟！ - 鹿血大哥！
- Bee! - Moose blood guy!!
- 你听到吗？ - 听到什么？
- You hear something? - Like what?
像是很小声的喊叫
Like tiny screaming.
把收音机关掉
Turn off the radio.
我们又见面了，小蜜蜂
Whassup, bee boy?
好啊，血哥
Hey, Blood.
目之所及，都是整排整排的蜂蜜罐
Just a row of honey jars, as far as the eye could see.
哇！
Wow!
所以我推测，这些卡车去的地方 就是蜂蜜的来源地
I assume wherever this truck goes is where they're getting it.
我的意思是说，这些蜂蜜是我们的
I mean, that honey's ours.
- 蜜蜂很团结 - 我们都住在一起
- Bees hang tight. - We're all jammed in.
是一个很紧密的群体
It's a close community.
我们蚊子不是，都是单干的，各顾各的
Not us, man. We on our own. Every mosquito on his own.
- 你遇到麻烦了怎么办？ - 你是蚊子，本身就是个麻烦
- What if you get in trouble? - You a mosquito, you in trouble.
没有人欢迎我们，杀无赦！杀、杀、杀无赦！
Nobody likes us. They just smack. See a mosquito, smack, smack!
起码我们出来见过世面了 你一定遇到过很多女孩
At least you're out in the world. You must meet girls.
雌蚊都想钓金龟婿，攀上飞蛾、蜻蜓之类的
Mosquito girls try to trade up, get with a moth, dragonfly.
雌蚊都不想嫁给蚊子
Mosquito girl don't want no mosquito.
我不是做梦吧！（它看见了送血车）
You got to be kidding me!
鹿血哥要走了哦！后会有期，蜜蜂老弟！
Mooseblood's about to leave the building! So long, bee!
- 弟兄们都在啊！ - 血哥来啦！
- Hey, guys! - Mooseblood!
我就知道你们会在这里，吸管准备好没？
I knew I'd catch y'all down here. Did you bring your crazy straw?
只要装到罐子里，贴个标签就赚钱了 真是无本万利啊
We throw it in jars, slap a label on it, and it's pretty much pure profit.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
蜜蜂只有针头那么丁点大的脑袋
A bee's got a brain the size of a pinhead.
蜜蜂都没脑的！
They are pinheads!
没脑
Pinhead.
- 看看新的喷雾枪 - 噢，太好啦，正合你意
- Check out the new smoker. - Oh, sweet. That's the one you want.
托马斯3000型！
The Thomas 3000!
喷雾枪？
Smoker?
射速90次/分，半自动 焦油含量，尼古丁的两倍
Ninety puffs a minute, semi-automatic. Twice the nicotine, all the tar.
吸几口，它们就立刻动弹不得
A couple breaths of this knocks them right out.
它们酿蜜，我们进“米”（赚钱）
They make the honey, and we make the money.
他们进“米”，我们酿蜜？
"They make the honey, and we make the money"?
天啊！
Oh, my!
发生什么事情了？你们没事吧？
What's going on? Are you OK?
没事，很快就好了
Yeah. It doesn't last too long.
你们怎么来了这里？你们知道 你们住在一个带假墙的假巢里吗？
Do you know you're in a fake hive with fake walls?
我们的蜂后搬到这里来了，我们别无选择
Our queen was moved here. We had no choice.
这是你们的蜂后吗？一个穿着裙子的老爷们儿！
This is your queen? That's a man in women's clothes!
一个男扮女装的蜂后！
That's a drag queen!
这又是怎么回事？
What is this?
不会吧！
Oh, no!
这里有上千个！
There's hundreds of them!
蜂蜜
Bee honey.
人类大规模厚颜无耻地盗取我们的蜂蜜！
Our honey is being brazenly stolen on a massive scale!
这比熊的所作所为还要恶劣！ 我一定要采取行动
This is worse than anything bears have done! I intend to do something.
噢，巴里，够了
Oh, Barry, stop.
谁告诉你是人类拿走了我们的蜂蜜？谣言罢了
Who told you humans are taking our honey? That's a rumor.
这些看起来像是谣言吗？
Do these look like rumors?
这一切都是阴谋，这些相片很明显是处理过的
That's a conspiracy theory. These are obviously doctored photos.
你怎么会真假不分呢？
How did you get mixed up in this?
因为他和人类说过话
He's been talking to humans.
- 什么？ - 和人类说话？
- What? - Talking to humans?!
他交了个人类女朋友，而且他们还约会过
He has a human girlfriend. And they make out!
还约会了？巴里！
Make out? Barry!
才没有
We do not.
- 你说你想过 - 你到底算哪边的？
- You wish you could. - Whose side are you on?
当然是蜜蜂这边
The bees!
有一次我和一只蟋蟀在圣安尼奥约会 那些脚让我一晚上都没睡好
I dated a cricket once in San Antonio. Those crazy legs kept me up all night.
巴里，你就想过这样的日子吗？
Barry, this is what you want to do with your life?
我这是为了大家好，没有人比蜜蜂更勤劳了！
I want to do it for all our lives. Nobody works harder than bees!
爸，我记得你回家的时候多累
Dad, I remember you coming home so overworked
你的手还在不停地搅拌，根本听不下来
your hands were still stirring. You couldn't stop.
我记得
I remember that.
他们凭什么拿走我们的蜂蜜？
What right do they have to our honey?
我们每年只用两杯蜂蜜，他们却无缘无故 用蜂蜜来做唇膏！
We live on two cups a year. They put it in lip balm for no reason whatsoever!
即使那是真的，蜜蜂能做什么？
Even if it's true, what can one bee do?
我要狠狠叮他们的要害
Sting them where it really hurts.
脸上！眼睛！
In the face! The eye!
- 那样很疼的 - 不是
- That would hurt. - No.
叮鼻子？绝
Up the nose? That's a killer.
只有一个地方可以让人类屈服，只有一个
There's only one place you can sting the humans, one place where it matters.
5点蜂房报道，蜂房唯一全天候新闻节目
Hive at Five, the hive's only full-hour action news source.
（反对蜜蜂作胡须）
No more bee beards!
由鲍勃・班布（直译为鲍勃嗡嗡叫） 在直播室为你主持
With Bob Bumble at the anchor desk.
斯多姆・斯汀格（直译为痛苦的暴风）为你 预报天气
Weather with Storm Stinger.
巴兹・拉瑞（直译为嗡嗡叫的幼虫）报道体育消息
Sports with Buzz Larvi.
和珍妮特・陈
And Jeanette Chung.
- 晚上好，我是鲍勃・班布 - 我是珍妮特・陈
- Good evening. I'm Bob Bumble. - And I'm Jeanette Chung.
头条新闻 一只来自三县的蜜蜂，巴里・班森
A tri-county bee, Barry Benson,
将要起诉人类盗取我们的蜂蜜
intends to sue the human race for stealing our honey,
灌装蜂蜜用以非法牟利！
packaging it and profiting from it illegally!
（这部分是模仿现实世界中CNN的一档晚间访谈类节目） 别忘了，明晚的蜂・拉里・金节目
Tomorrow night on Bee Larry King,
我们将邀请三位前蜂后坐客本节目 来谈谈他们的新书
we'll have three former queens here in our studio, discussing their new book,
《优雅众女士》，本周精彩播出就在六角电视台
Classy Ladies, out this week on Hexagon.
今晚我们的嘉宾是巴里・班森
Tonight we're talking to Barry Benson.
你有没有想过，“我只不过是蜂房里的 一个小孩，我做不来这个？”
Did you ever think, "I'm a kid from the hive. I can't do this"?
蜜蜂从来不畏惧去改变世界
Bees have never been afraid to change the world.
难道你忘了蜂・哥伦布？蜂・甘地？蜂・耶稣？
What about Bee Columbus? Bee Gandhi? Bejesus?
作为蜜蜂一员，你不应该想着控告人类
Where I'm from, we'd never sue humans.
我们应该想着捏糖球或者储存糖料
We were thinking of stickball or candy stores.
您今年多大了？
How old are you?
我跟你说吧，整个蜜蜂社会在 这个案子上都支持你
The bee community is supporting you in this case,
因为它必将成为蜜蜂的世纪大审判
which will be the trial of the bee century.
谢谢你，拉里
You know, they have a Larry King in the human world too.
你知道么，人类社会也有个拉里・金
叫这名字的很多，下周的蜂・拉里・金节目…
It's a common name. Next week...
不不不，我是说他看起来跟你挺像的 也主持个节目，穿个背带裤，后面也有这些彩点
He looks like you and has a show and suspenders and colored dots...
下周的蜂・拉里・金节目…
Next week...
带着老花镜，画面下面播着字幕，显示着嘉宾说的话 而这些话你还正在听着呢 （BeeNN台 巴里・班森说：“画面下面播着字幕…）
Glasses, quotes on the bottom from the guest even though you just heard 'em.
巴里！下周是熊周！它们危险吓人 本台将现场直播 （显示着嘉宾说的话…）
Bear Week next week! They're scary, hairy and here live.
总是向前倾着身子，耸着个肩膀 喜欢斜视，还…犹太味十足 （而这些话你还正在听着呢）
Always leans forward, pointy shoulders, squinty eyes, very Jewish.
（维纳莎花店）
在网球场上，你要攻击对手的弱项
In tennis, you attack at the point of weakness!
但那可是我奶奶啊，肯，她都81岁了
It was my grandmother, Ken. She's 81.
宝贝，她的反手球对我来说可是个好机会啊 我怎么可能放过？
Honey, her backhand's a joke! I'm not gonna take advantage of that?
安静点，行不，我这在做正经事呢
Quiet, please. Actual work going on here.
- 难道还是上次那只蜜蜂？ - 是的，是我！
- Is that that same bee? - Yes, it is!
我正帮他指控人类呢
I'm helping him sue the human race.
- 你好 - 你好，蜜蜂
- Hello. - Hello, bee.
这位是肯
This is Ken.
是的，我记得你，丛林靴，10号半的 伐柏拉姆牌，肯定没错
Yeah, I remember you. Timberland, size ten and a half. Vibram sole, I believe.
为什么他又说起话了？
Why does he talk again?
听着，你最好离开因为我们现在可忙了
Listen, you better go 'cause we're really busy working.
可是今天是我们的“酸奶之夜”！
But it's our yogurt night!
拜拜
Bye-bye.
为什么过个“酸奶之夜”这么费劲啊？！
Why is yogurt night so difficult?!
噢，可怜的小家伙们 你们两个已经足足搞了几个钟头了
You poor thing. You two have been at this for hours!
没错，亚当能来这儿可是帮了“大忙”了
Yes, and Adam here has been a huge help.
（肉桂卷）
- 糖衣… - 要几块糖？
- Frosting... - How many sugars?
就一块吧，我尽量少用对手的产品
Just one. I try not to use the competition.
嗯，你干嘛要帮我呢？
So why are you helping me?
蜜蜂们有着让人尊敬的品行
Bees have good qualities.
这感觉挺好，免得成天惦记花店
And it takes my mind off the shop.
不知道为什么，鲜花被取代了 人们全都改用气球花束了
Instead of flowers, people are giving balloon bouquets now.
是啊，那个也不错，前提是你只有三岁
Those are great, if you're three.
还有人造花呢
And artificial flowers.
-噢，那听起来真让人抓狂 -没错，我也是
- Oh, those just get me psychotic! - Yeah, me too.
塑料花会导致蜂刺折断、传粉失去意义
Bent stingers, pointless pollination.
蜜蜂一定不喜欢这些伪造的塑料货！
Bees must hate those fake things!
最糟的就是一朵水仙花无粉可传
Nothing worse than a daffodil that's had work done.
嗯嗯，或许这个可以让我们稍稍得些补偿
Maybe this could make up for it a little bit.
- 你应该知道，巴里，这次诉讼可非同小可 - 我猜是吧
- This lawsuit's a pretty big deal. - I guess.
你确定你真的想把它寄出去吗？
You sure you want to go through with it?
我确不确定？一旦我控诉人类成功 他们再也不敢说
Am I sure? When I'm done with the humans, they won't be able
“小蜜糖，我回来了”，却不交一分税
to say, "Honey, I'm home," without paying a royalty!
这里是曼哈顿市中心，一切都这么不可思议
It's an incredible scene here in downtown Manhattan,
在这里所有人都有焦急地等待着 因为这将是历史上的第一次
where the world anxiously waits, because for the first time in history,
我们将亲自见证一只蜜蜂是否真的 可以开口说话
we will hear for ourselves if a honeybee can actually speak.
我们来这儿到底是为了什么，巴里？
What have we gotten into here, Barry?
我也不知道，但是这里确实挺大，不是吗？
It's pretty big, isn't it?
真不敢相信有这么多人，大白天的没事做
I can't believe how many humans don't work during the day.
你猜这些资产上亿美元的跨国食品公司 请得起顶级大律师吗？
You think billion-dollar multinational food companies have good lawyers?
所有人都站到路障后面
Everybody needs to stay behind the barricade.
- 怎么了？ - 我也不知道，突然打了个冷颤
- What's the matter? - I don't know, I just got a chill.
嗯，如果不是你们蜜蜂的话
Well, if it isn't the bee team.
我还喝不着这个（蜂蜜）呢？
You boys work on this?
全体起立！有请尊敬的法官邦博顿大人
All rise! The Honorable Judge Bumbleton presiding.
好，第4475号案件
All right. Case number 4475,
纽约高等法院 巴里・蜂・班森指控蜂蜜产业公司
Superior Court of New York, Barry Bee Benson v. The Honey Industry
现在正式开庭
is now in session.
蒙哥马利先生，你是全权代表 这五家食品公司的，是不是？
Mr. Montgomery, you're representing the five food companies collectively?
全权的
A privilege.
班森先生…你是不是代表了全世界的蜜蜂？
Mr. Benson... you're representing all the bees of the world?
开个玩笑，是的，法官大人 我们已经准备就续了
I'm kidding. Yes, Your Honor, we're ready to proceed.
蒙哥马利先生，由你首先做开庭陈述，请吧
Mr. Montgomery, your opening statement, please.
陪审团的各位女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
我的奶奶是名普通的妇女
my grandmother was a simple woman.
出生在一个农场，她相信人类有权
Born on a farm, she believed it was man's divine right
从上帝恩赐的大自然万物中得益
to benefit from the bounty of nature God put before us.
如果我们活在一个逻辑颠倒的世界 如班森先生所想的话
If we lived in the topsy-turvy world Mr. Benson imagines,
想想那意味着什么吧
just think of what would it mean.
也许，我不得不去跟桑蚕谈判
I would have to negotiate with the silkworm
因为我穿着带着松紧带的裤子
for the elastic in my britches!
会说话的蜜蜂！
Talking bee!
我们怎么确定这不是什么
How do we know this isn't some sort of
好莱坞全新使用的全息动态影像捕捉技术
holographic motion-picture-capture Hollywood wizardry?
他们可以使用激光电波！
They could be using laser beams!
机器人！口技！克隆！就我们所知
Robotics! Ventriloquism! Cloning! For all we know,
它极可能是堆类固醇做的！
he could be on steroids!
班森先生？
Mr. Benson?
女士们先生们，这里绝对没有什么障眼法
Ladies and gentlemen, there's no trickery here.
我只不过是只普普通通的蜜蜂 作为蜜蜂，蜂蜜对我来说极为重要
I'm just an ordinary bee. Honey's pretty important to me.
它对所有蜜蜂来说都很重要，我们创造了蜂蜜！
It's important to all bees. We invented it!
我们制造它，而且我们用生命来捍卫它
We make it. And we protect it with our lives.
不幸的是，这里有些人
Unfortunately, there are some people in this room
认为他们可以从我们身边抢走 任何他们想要的东西
who think they can take it from us
而就因为我们长得很渺小！ 所以我希望，当这一切都结束之后
'cause we're the little guys! I'm hoping that, after this is all over,
你们就会明白，夺走我们的蜂蜜 不仅仅是夺走我们的所有
you'll see how, by taking our honey, you not only take everything we have
更是夺走了我们的生命！
but everything we are!
真希望他一直穿成这样，帅极了！
I wish he'd dress like that all the time. So nice!
传第一位证人上庭
Call your first witness.
那么，克劳斯・范德海登先生 “蜂蜜农庄”的总裁，你的公司可真不小啊
So, Mr. Klauss Vanderhayden of Honey Farms, big company you have.
我想是的
I suppose so.
而且我还查出你还拥有 “蜂蜜毁灭者”和“蜂蜜收割者”！
I see you also own Honeyburton and Honron!
是的，他们为我们农场提供养蜂人
Yes, they provide beekeepers for our farms.
“养蜂人”，我觉得这是个很有迷惑性的字眼
Beekeeper. I find that to be a very disturbing term.
我想你们没雇佣“放蜂人”吧，是不是？
I don't imagine you employ any bee-free-ers, do you?
- 没有 - 不好意思，我听不见
- No. - I couldn't hear you.
- 没有 - 没有
- No. - No.
因为你们不会把蜜蜂放出来的 你们把蜜蜂关着，不仅如此
Because you don't free bees. You keep bees. Not only that,
看来你还认为熊的形象用来做蜂蜜罐比较合适
it seems you thought a bear would be an appropriate image for a jar of honey.
嗯嗯，他们都是比较可爱的动物
They're very lovable creatures.
瑜珈熊，福滋熊，泰迪熊
Yogi Bear, Fozzie Bear, Build-A-Bear.
没错，你是说像这个一样？
You mean like this?
熊专杀蜜蜂！
Bears kill bees!
你会愿意让一头熊钻到你的卧室吗？
How'd you like his head crashing through your living room?!
它会咬烂你的睡床！撕烂你的睡枕！
Biting into your couch! Spitting out your throw pillows!
好了，够了，带它出去吧
OK, that's enough. Take him away.
嗯，斯汀（Sting，叮）先生，谢谢你能出席 你的名字让我很感兴趣
So, Mr. Sting, thank you for being here. Your name intrigues me.
- 我在哪听过吗？ - 我以前参加过警察乐队（The Police）
- Where have I heard it before? - I was with a band called The Police.
但是你从来没有当过警察什么的，是不是？
But you've never been a police officer, have you?
没有，我没当过
No, I haven't.
没有，你没当过，那么现在我们 又有了另一个例子
No, you haven't. And so here we have yet another example
那就是蜜蜂文化肆意被人类盗用
of bee culture casually stolen by a human
用来做为那些只会乱蹦的人的艺名
for nothing more than a prance-about stage name.
噢，拜托
Oh, please.
你有没有曾经被叮过，斯汀先生？
Have you ever been stung, Mr. Sting?
因为我觉得有点被叮的剌痛，斯汀先生
Because I'm feeling a little stung, Sting.
或者我应该叫你…戈登・M・萨默尔先生！
Or should I say... Mr. Gordon M. Sumner!
那不是他的真名吗？！你们这群白痴！
That's not his real name?! You idiots!
利奥塔先生，首先我要呈上我迟到的祝贺
Mr. Liotta, first, belated congratulations on
祝贺你凭借《ER》 获得2005年度艾美奖最佳客串男演员 （2005年黄金段艾美奖 雷・利奥塔 剧情类最佳客串男演员）
your Emmy win for a guest spot on ER in 2005.
谢谢，谢谢！
Thank you. Thank you.
我看过你的履历，你真是太帅了
I see from your resume that you're devilishly handsome
就像奶油翻浆，帅的几乎冒油了
with a churning inner turmoil that's ready to blow.
我只是做我喜欢的事，这也算犯罪吗？
I enjoy what I do. Is that a crime?
现在还不是，不过，难道这就是你的初衷？
Not yet it isn't. But is this what it's come to for you?
剥削弱小、无助的小蜜蜂们
Exploiting tiny, helpless bees so you don't
这样你就用不着成天排练节目 背你的台词了，啊，先生？
have to rehearse your part and learn your lines, sir?
小心点，班森！ 我现在就可以给你点颜色看看！
Watch it, Benson! I could blow right now!
他不是好家伙！他是个坏家伙！ （引用利奥塔主演的电影《好家伙》）
This isn't a goodfella. This is a badfella!
为什么没人一脚踩死这只小虫子 这样大家都可以回家了！
Why doesn't someone just step on this creep, and we can all go home?!
- 肃静，法庭上请保持肃静！ - 你们都是这么想的！
- Order in this court! - You're all thinking it!
肃静！肃静，我说肃静！
Order! Order, I say!
- 说出来啊！ - 利奥塔先生，请坐下！
- Say it! - Mr. Liotta, please sit down!
（原告竟是小蜜蜂！！！）
（蜜蜂指控人类：紧急休庭）
（《每日综艺》：公司撤资利奥塔的项目）
我觉得那样棒极了，那头熊表现十分到位！
I think it was awfully nice of that bear to pitch in like that.
跟你说吧，我想陪审团是站在我们这一边的
I think the jury's on our side.
我们做的都是对的吗，我是说，合法的？
Are we doing everything right, legally?
我只是个养花的
I'm a florist.
是啊是啊，嗯，敬伟大的团队
Right. Well, here's to a great team.
敬伟大的团队！
To a great team!
嗯，你好
Well, hello.
-  噢，肯！ - 你好
- Ken! - Hello.
我没想到你还能来
I didn't think you were coming.
那个，我只是迟到罢了 我试过打电话，不过…这破电池
No, I was just late. I tried to call, but... the battery.
我不想浪费这一桌美餐，于是我叫了巴里 幸运的是他正好有空
I didn't want all this to go to waste, so I called Barry. Luckily, he was free.
噢，确实很幸运
Oh, that was lucky.
还有点儿吃的，我可以帮你热一下
There's a little left. I could heat it up.
对，把它热一下，当然了，我不在意
Yeah, heat it up, sure, whatever.
噢，我听说你是个不折不扣的网球手
So I hear you're quite a tennis player.
我自己不大擅长这项运动，那个网球很是缠人
I'm not much for the game myself. The ball's a little grabby.
那个是我通常坐的位置，就是…那里
That's where I usually sit. Right... there.
肯，巴里看过了你的简历
Ken, Barry was looking at your resume,
他也同意我的看法，用筷子吃东西不算什么技术
and he agreed with me that eating with chopsticks isn't really a special skill.
你真以为我看不懂你在干嘛？
You think I don't see what you're doing?
我明白，确实很难找份合适的工作 我们在这点上有共识
I know how hard it is to find the rightjob. We have that in common.
是吗？
Do we?
蜜蜂是百分百的可以就业 可惜我们净做些类似挑垃圾的活
Bees have 100 percent employment, but we do jobs like taking the crud out.
那正是我考虑要做的事
That's just what I was thinking about doing.
肯，我让巴里用你的剃须刀来刮绒毛 希望你别介意
Ken, I let Barry borrow your razor for his fuzz. I hope that was all right.
我去冲一冲这根老化的蜂刺
I'm going to drain the old stinger.
好的，你请自便
Yeah, you do that.
看看这个
Look at that.
你知道不，我刚刚看到它
You know, I've just about had it
正好想起来你的心灵小游戏
with your little mind games.
- 什么东西？ - 《意大利时尚》杂志！
- What's that? - Italian Vogue.
我的妈呀，那可有太多页了
Mamma mia, that's a lot of pages.
都是些广告
A lot of ads.
还记得维纳莎说的话吗 为什么你的命会比我的值钱？
Remember what Van said, why is your life more valuable than mine?
奇怪，我就是想不起来了！
Funny, I just can't seem to recall that!
我看这有东西发臭了！
I think something stinks in here!
我喜欢这种花的味道
I love the smell of flowers.
那么你喜不喜欢火的味道？
How do you like the smell of flames?!
没那么喜欢
Not as much.
我是蟑螂！保持中立！
Water bug! Not taking sides!
肯，看看我，带着唇膏盖帽子，真是可怜的很
Ken, I'm wearing a Chapstick hat! This is pathetic!
我来帮你解难！
I've got issues!
好啊，好啊，好啊，好好冲个凉吧
Well, well, well, a royal flush!
- 你只是虚张声势 - 噢，是吗？
- You're bluffing. - Am I?
冲浪来喽，伙计！
Surf's up, dude!
啊，便池水！
Poo water!
这块洼滩可不怎么平
That bowl is gnarly.
除了那些脏兮兮的黄圈！
Except for those dirty yellow rings!
肯尼思！你在干嘛？！
Kenneth! What are you doing?!
你知道吗，我根本不喜欢蜂蜜！我连吃都不吃！
You know, I don't even like honey! I don't eat it!
我们得谈谈！
We need to talk!
他只不过是只小蜜蜂！
He's just a little bee!
而且我发现他是我这么长时间以来见过的 最好的蜜蜂
And he happens to be the nicest bee I've met in a long time!
“这么长时间以来”？你在说什么啊？！ 还有其他的虫子闯进你的生活？
Long time? What are you talking about?! Are there other bugs in your life?
没有，但是却有些其他东西像虫子一样 烦着我的生活，而你就是其中一个！
No, but there are other things bugging me in life. And you're one of them!
好极了！会说话的蜜蜂、不过“酸奶之夜”…
Fine! Talking bees, no yogurt night...
我的神经已经受不了这过山车似的折磨了！
My nerves are fried from riding on this emotional roller coaster!
再见了，肯
Goodbye, Ken.
告诉你一件事
And for your information,
我喜欢无糖食品，人工甜料，人造的！
I prefer sugar-free, artificial sweeteners made by man!
对此我很抱歉
I'm sorry about all that.
我知道它吃完会有余味！ 我喜欢那个！
I know it's got an aftertaste! I like it!
我总觉着肯和我之间有些隔阂
I always felt there was some kind of barrier between Ken and me.
我却没法逾越，噢，算了
I couldn't overcome it. Oh, well.
你没问题吧，关于明天的庭审？
Are you OK for the trial?
我想蒙哥马利先生已经黔驴技穷了
I believe Mr. Montgomery is about out of ideas.
我们想有请巴里・蜂・班森先生上证人席
We would like to call Mr. Barry Benson Bee to the stand.
好主意！这回你就可以看看为什么他被 视为顶级大律师了…
Good idea! You can really see why he's considered one of the best lawyers...
好吧
Yeah.
莱顿，你必须得想点奇招
Layton, you've gotta weave some magic
说服这些陪审员，否则的话一切都完了
with this jury, or it's gonna be all over.
别担心，加莫先生，只一件事就可让 陪审团回心转意
Don't worry. The only thing I have to do to turn this jury around
那就是让他们想起他们最反感蜜蜂的什么
is to remind them of what they don't like about bees.
- 你带了镊子吧？ - 你不过敏吧？
- You got the tweezers? - Are you allergic?
只对失败过敏，孩子，只对失败过敏！
Only to losing, son. Only to losing.
蜂・班森先生，我想问个大家都关心的问题
Mr. Benson Bee, I'll ask you what I think we'd all like to know.
你到底和那位女士…
What exactly is your relationship
是什么关系？
to that woman?
我们是朋友
We're friends.
- 好朋友？ - 是的
- Good friends? - Yes.
有多好？你们住在一起吗？
How good? Do you live together?
等一下，这些都是关于…
Wait a minute...
你是不是她的小…
Are you her little...
…同居小虫？
...bedbug?
我看过关于蜜蜂的记录片约有一两部 从中我了解到
I've seen a bee documentary or two. From what I understand,
难道不是你们的蜂后生下 你们所有小孩吗
doesn't your queen give birth to all the bee children?
- 是的，但是… - 那就是说那些不是你真正的父母！
- Yeah, but... - So those aren't your real parents!
- 噢，巴里… - 不，他们是！
- Oh, Barry... - Yes, they are!
快拉住我！
Hold me back!
你是只私生蜂，不是吗，班森？
You're an illegitimate bee, aren't you, Benson?
他竟然公开诋毁蜜蜂！
He's denouncing bees!
难道你们与之约会的不都是兄妹吗？
Don't y'all date your cousins?
- 反对！ - 我要蜇死这家伙！
- Objection! - I'm going to pincushion this guy!
亚当，不要！这正是他想要的！
Adam, don't! It's what he wants!
啊，我被袭了！
Oh, I'm hit!!
噢，上帝！我被袭了！
Oh, lordy, I am hit!
肃静！肃静！
Order! Order!
毒液！毒液正贯穿我全身！
The venom! The venom is coursing through my veins!
我要被毒死了，就是被那只带翅膀的畜牲！
I have been felled by a winged beast of destruction!
你们看到了？没法对它们平等相待 它们兽性未除！
You see? You can't treat them like equals! They're striped savages!
叮人是他们脑里唯一的事，这就是蜜蜂！
Stinging's the only thing they know! It's their way!
- 亚当，坚持住 - 我的双腿失去知觉了
- Adam, stay with me. - I can't feel my legs.
哪位天使姐姐能帮我吸吸毒
What angel of mercy will come forward to suck the poison
从我这翘起的屁股上？
from my heaving buttocks?
我命令大家保持肃静，这是法庭！
I will have order in this court. Order!
肃静，请肃静！
Order, please!
这起关于蜜蜂起诉人类的案件
The case of the honeybees versus the human race
却反将矛头指向了蜜蜂一族
took a pointed turn against the bees
就在昨天他们的一位成员蜇伤了 莱顿・T・蒙哥马利
yesterday when one of their legal team stung Layton T. Montgomery.
- 嗨，兄弟 - 嗨
- Hey, buddy. - Hey.
- 还很疼吗？ - 是啊
- Is there much pain? - Yeah.
我…
I...
我搞砸了整个案子，是不是？
I blew the whole case, didn't I?
这不要紧，重要的是你还活着，你本来会死的
It doesn't matter. What matters is you're alive. You could have died.
我倒宁愿死掉，看看我
I'd be better off dead. Look at me.
这是他们从楼下的餐厅弄来的 夹在金枪鱼三明治中的
They got it from the cafeteria downstairs, in a tuna sandwich.
你看看，这还有一点芹菜挂在上面
Look, there's a little celery still on it.
那是一种什么感觉，当你叮人的时候？
What was it like to sting someone?
我也没法解释，就感觉…
I can't explain it. It was all...
血往上涌，然后…然后就感觉心醉神迷
All adrenaline and then... and then ecstasy!
好吧
All right.
你认为那是个陷阱？
You think it was all a trap?
当然了，对不起，是我把咱们卷进来的
Of course. I'm sorry. I flew us right into this.
我们在想什么？看看咱俩 只不过是世界上一对小虫子而已
What were we thinking? Look at us. We're just a couple of bugs in this world.
人类会怎么对付我们，万一他们赢了的话？
What will the humans do to us if they win?
我不知道
I don't know.
我听说他们把蟑螂养在旅馆里 听起来也不坏
I hear they put the roaches in motels. That doesn't sound so bad.
亚当，它们是住进去了，但是没人出来啊！
Adam, they check in, but they don't check out!
噢，我的天
Oh, my.
能叫护士关上那扇窗吗？
Could you get a nurse to close that window?
- 为什么？ - 有烟进来
- Why? - The smoke.
蜜蜂可不吸烟
Bees don't smoke.
对啊，蜜蜂可不吸烟！
Right. Bees don't smoke.
蜜蜂是不吸烟！但是有些蜜蜂却不得不吸！
Bees don't smoke! But some bees are smoking.
对呀！我们的案子不就这么回事吗！
That's it! That's our case!
怎么回事？案子还没完？
It is? It's not over?
快起来，穿好衣服，我得去个地方
Get dressed. I've gotta go somewhere.
你回到法庭上拖延时间，能拖多久就拖多久
Get back to the court and stall. Stall any way you can.
接着，如果你们都已经做完了第29步 那么可以让它出海了
And assuming you've done step 29 correctly, you're ready for the tub.
弗莱曼先生
Mr. Flayman.
是的？是的，法官大人！
Yes? Yes, Your Honor!
怎么还不见你们其他的组员？
Where is the rest of your team?
是这样的，法官大人，说起来挺有趣
Well, Your Honor, it's interesting.
蜜蜂从小就受训应对突发事件
Bees are trained to fly haphazardly,
结果却导致我们有着很有差的时间观念
and as a result, we don't make very good time.
我听过一个非常有趣的故事，是关于…
I actually heard a funny story about...
法官大人，是不是这些荒谬的虫子们
Your Honor, haven't these ridiculous bugs
已经糟蹋太多法庭的宝贵时间了？
taken up enough of this court's valuable time?
还要多久这种荒谬的恶作剧才能有个头儿？
How much longer will we allow these absurd shenanigans to go on?
它们一直拿不出有利的证据来支持它们的指控
They have presented no compelling evidence to support their charges
我的委托人做的根本就是合法生意
against my clients, who run legitimate businesses.
我要求撤消全部指控！
I move for a complete dismissal of this entire case!
弗莱曼先生，恐怕
Mr. Flayman, I'm afraid I'm going
我不得不考虑一下蒙哥马利先生的动议了
to have to consider Mr. Montgomery's motion.
但是您不能这样！这是件非比寻常的案子
But you can't! We have a terrific case.
你的证据在哪？你的证物又在哪？
Where is your proof? Where is the evidence?
让我看看那把喷雾枪！
Show me the smoking gun!
等一下，法官大人！你想要看喷雾枪？
Hold it, Your Honor! You want a smoking gun?
这就是那把喷雾枪！
Here is your smoking gun.
这是什么东西？
What is that?
这是蜜蜂喷雾枪！
It's a bee smoker!
什么，这个？这个根本无害的小装置？
What, this? This harmless little contraption?
这连苍蝇都伤不了，何况一只蜜蜂
This couldn't hurt a fly, let alone a bee.
尊敬的陪审员们，看看发生了什么
Look at what has happened
那些蜜蜂从来没被问过：“吸不吸烟？”
to bees who have never been asked, "Smoking or non?"
难道这就是自然界对我们的本意吗？
Is this what nature intended for us?
被强迫受制于喷雾枪
To be forcibly addicted to smoke machines
还有那些人造的木质工作坊？
and man-made wooden slat work camps?
终其一生却只是做个蜂蜜奴隶 倒让那些白人得利？
Living out our lives as honey slaves to the white man?
- 这下我们怎么办？ - 他打的是种族牌
- What are we gonna do? - He's playing the species card.
女士们先生们，谢谢你们，解放这些蜜蜂吧！
Ladies and gentlemen, please, free these bees!
解放蜜蜂！解放蜜蜂！
Free the bees! Free the bees!
解放蜜蜂！
Free the bees!
解放蜜蜂！解放蜜蜂！
Free the bees! Free the bees!
法庭宣判胜方为蜜蜂！
The court finds in favor of the bees!
维纳莎，我们赢了！
Vanessa, we won!
我就知道你做得到！来击个掌！
I knew you could do it! High-five!
噢，对不起
Sorry.
我没事！你知道这意味着什么吗？
I'm OK! You know what this means?
所有的蜂蜜都将归蜜蜂所有！
All the honey will finally belong to the bees.
从此我们再也不用成天卖命地干活了
Now we won't have to work so hard all the time.
这极不合理地颠倒了自然界的平衡，班森
This is an unholy perversion of the balance of nature, Benson.
你会后悔的
You'll regret this.
巴里，到底一共有多少蜂蜜？
Barry, how much honey is out there?
好好好，一个一个来
All right. One at a time.
巴里，你穿什么牌子的衣服？
Barry, who are you wearing?
我上身穿的是拉夫・劳伦 但是我不穿裤子
My sweater is Ralph Lauren, and I have no pants.
- 如果蒙哥马利说得对怎么办？ - 你这是什么意思？
- What if Montgomery's right? - What do you mean?
我们按照蜜蜂的方式生活了这么久了 2700万年啊
We've been living the bee way a long time, 27 million years.
祝贺你胜诉，你要求什么做为胜诉赔偿？
Congratulations on your victory. What will you demand as a settlement?
首先，我们要求彻底停止蜜蜂的人工作坊
First, we'll demand a complete shutdown of all bee work camps.
然后，我们会要回所有属于我们的蜂蜜
Then we want back the honey that was ours to begin with,
绝不放过任何一滴
every last drop.
我们要求终止发行那些熊罐子，它们比那些
We demand an end to the glorification of the bear as anything more
污秽变味的破烂儿机器强不了多少
than a filthy, smelly, bad-breath stink machine.
我相信，我们都知道它们在森林里的所做所为
We're all aware of what they do in the woods.
等我的信号
Wait for my signal.
开枪
Take him out.
他会稍感恶心，几小时之后，他就会恢复正常
He'll have nauseous for a few hours, then he'll be fine.
而且我们再也不会充许反蜜蜂类的昵称…
And we will no longer tolerate bee-negative nicknames...
可是这只是个娱乐性的艺名
But it's just a prance-about stage name!
…不必要地将蜂蜜添加到伪劣的健康产品中
...unnecessary inclusion of honey in bogus health products
还有那些所谓“健康”的人类喝茶用的调味料 （成份：蜂蜜）
and la-dee-da human tea-time snack garnishments.
还有那些所谓“养生”的人类喝茶用的调味料 （香蜂蜜）
没法喘气了
Can't breathe.
放下来，伙计们！
Bring it in, boys!
就放在那儿！好极了
Hold it right there! Good.
开阀门
Tap it.
巴兹威尔先生，我们刚刚装了三杯 可是那还有几百加仑正流进来
Mr. Buzzwell, we just passed three cups, and there's gallons more coming!
- 我想我们得把生产线关了 - 关了？我们之前从未关过
- I think we need to shut down! - Shut down? We've never shut down.
关掉蜂蜜生产线！
Shut down honey production!
停止生产蜂蜜！
Stop making honey!
转动钥匙，老兄！
Turn your key, sir!
我们现在干些什么？
What do we do now?
跳水喽！
Cannonball!
我们停止了蜂蜜生产线！
We're shutting honey production!
任务中止
Mission abort.
中止传粉，停止采蜜，返回基地
Aborting pollination and nectar detail. Returning to base.
（店内已无花）
亚当，你肯定想不到，外面有多少蜂蜜
Adam, you wouldn't believe how much honey was out there.
噢，是吗？
Oh, yeah?
发生什么事了？人都哪去了？
What's going on? Where is everybody?
- 他们都出去庆祝了？ - 他们都呆在家里
- Are they out celebrating? - They're home.
他们不知道该干嘛了，出来晒太阳，回屋睡觉
They don't know what to do. Laying out, sleeping in.
我听说你的叔叔卡尔出发去圣安东尼奥了 跟一支蟋蟀同路
I heard your Uncle Carl was on his way to San Antonio with a cricket.
至少我们要回了我们的蜂蜜
At least we got our honey back.
有时我就想，人们喜欢蜂蜜，那又怎么样？ 谁不喜欢呢？
Sometimes I think, so what if humans liked our honey? Who wouldn't?
这是世界上最值得骄傲的事！ 我很荣幸成为制作蜂蜜的一员
It's the greatest thing in the world! I was excited to be part of making it.
这是我的新桌子，这是我的新工作 我希望把它认认真真地做好
This was my new desk. This was my new job. I wanted to do it really well.
可是现在…
And now...
现在我做不到了
Now I can't.
我不明白，为什么他们都不高兴了
I don't understand why they're not happy.
我们拥有这么多 我原以为他们的生活会更好的！
I thought their lives would be better!
它们什么也不干了，太让人意外了 蜂蜜真的是改变了它们
They're doing nothing. It's amazing. Honey really changes people.
你一点也不知道到底发生什么事了，是不是？
You don't have any idea what's going on, do you?
- 你想给我看些什么？ - 这个
- What did you want to show me? - This.
这里怎么了？
What happened here?
这只不过是冰山一角
That is not the half of it.
噢，不，噢，我的天！
Oh, no. Oh, my.
它们都调谢了
They're all wilting.
看起来可不是那么好，是不是？
Doesn't look very good, does it?
没错
No.
那么，你觉得这是谁的错呢？
And whose fault do you think that is?
你知道，我猜可能是蜜蜂们
You know, I'm gonna guess bees.
蜜蜂们？
Bees?
事实上，是我
Specifically, me.
我没想到蜜蜂不产蜜会影响到所有其他的事物
I didn't think bees not needing to make honey would affect all these things.
不仅仅是花儿，水果，蔬菜 它们都需要蜜蜂
It's notjust flowers. Fruits, vegetables, they all need bees.
这成了我们的学术研究实验了
That's our whole SAT test right there.
就是说，你拿走你们的产品 却影响了整个动物界
Take away produce, that affects the entire animal kingdom.
然后接着，当然了…
And then, of course...
是人类？
The human species?
那么，如果没有授粉的话
So if there's no more pollination,
这么说这里将会是一片荒芜了，是不是？
it could all just go south here, couldn't it?
我知道，这其中也有我的错
I know this is also partly my fault.
来个互相残杀怎么样？
How about a suicide pact?
咱们得怎么做？
How do we do it?
- 我来蜇你，你来踩我 - 那只不过是让你死了两次而已
- I'll sting you, you step on me. - Thatjust kills you twice.
没错，没错
Right, right.
听着，巴里…对不起了，但是我必须得走了
Listen, Barry... sorry, but I gotta get going.
我必须要站出来说句话了
I had to open my mouth and talk.
维纳莎？
Vanessa?
维纳莎？你为什么要离开？你想要去哪？
Vanessa? Why are you leaving? Where are you going?
去看一看最后一次玫瑰展示锦标赛 地点在帕萨迪纳
To the final Tournament of Roses parade in Pasadena.
他们把比赛调到了这一周 因为所有的花都快死了
They've moved it to this weekend because all the flowers are dying.
这是最后的机会了，以后再也看不到了
It's the last chance I'll ever have to see it.
维纳莎，我只是想说真对不起 我从没想过事情会变成这样
Vanessa, I just wanna say I'm sorry. I never meant it to turn out like this.
我明白，我也一样
I know. Me neither.
玫瑰展示锦标赛，玫瑰自己没法做运动
Tournament of Roses. Roses can't do sports.
等一下，玫瑰，玫瑰？
Wait a minute. Roses. Roses?
玫瑰！
Roses!
维纳莎！
Vanessa!
玫瑰？！
Roses?!
巴里？
Barry?
- 玫瑰是花啊！ - 是啊，是花啊
- Roses are flowers! - Yes, they are.
鲜花，蜜蜂，传粉！
Flowers, bees, pollen!
我知道，那就是为什么这是最后一次展示了
I know. That's why this is the last parade.
也许不是呢，你能让他开慢点吗？
Maybe not. Could you ask him to slow down?
您能开慢点吗？
Could you slow down?
巴里！
Barry!
好吧，我犯了一个大错误 这是个天大的灾难，都是我的错
OK, I made a huge mistake. This is a total disaster, all my fault.
是的，差不多是这样
Yes, it kind of is.
我已经毁了这个星球，我本是想帮你
I've ruined the planet. I wanted to help you
扩展你的花店，相反，却把它搞砸了
with the flower shop. I've made it worse.
实际上，店已经彻底关门大吉了
Actually, it's completely closed down.
我还以为你是要重新装修呢
I thought maybe you were remodeling.
不过我有了个新想法，比之前的几个加起来都好
But I have another idea, and it's greater than my previous ideas combined.
我一点也不想听！
I don't want to hear it!
好吧，他们有玫瑰，玫瑰有花粉
All right, they have the roses, the roses have the pollen.
我认识所有的蜜蜂 以及这个公园里的所有植物和鲜花
I know every bee, plant and flower bud in this park.
我们所要做的就是把它们以前有的还给它们
All we gotta do is get what they've got back here with what we've got.
- 蜜蜂 - 公园
- Bees. - Park.
- 花粉 - 鲜花
- Pollen! - Flowers.
- 传粉！ - 贯穿整个国家！
- Repollination! - Across the nation!
玫瑰锦标赛 帕萨迪纳，加利福尼亚 （玫瑰赛 展区）
Tournament of Roses, Pasadena, California.
他们什么都没有，除了花，就是彩车跟棉花糖
They've got nothing but flowers, floats and cotton candy.
安保会非常严格
Security will be tight.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
维纳莎・布鲁姆，国际送花会的
Vanessa Bloome, FTD.
官方花卉业务，这是真的
Official floral business. It's real.
不好意思，女士，很靓的胸针哦
Sorry, ma'am. Nice brooch.
谢谢，是份礼物
Thank you. It was a gift.
一旦入场，就只管选对彩车
Once inside, we just pick the right float.
那台“公主与绿豆”怎么样？
How about The Princess and the Pea?
我就是那个公主，你么，可以当绿豆
I could be the princess, and you could be the pea!
好的，我明白了
Yes, I got it.
- 对不起，我迟到了，我该坐哪？ - 你是什么？
- Where should I sit? - What are you?
- 我想我就是那个绿豆 - 绿豆？
- I believe I'm the pea. - The pea?
它应该是床垫下面
It goes under the mattresses.
- 这个童话里会有点不同，亲爱的 - 我要去找司仪
- Not in this fairy tale, sweetheart. - I'm getting the marshal.
你这样做的话整个会展就毁了
You do that! This whole parade is a fiasco!
让我们来看看这个家伙能干嘛
Let's see what this baby'll do.
嘿，你们干嘛呢！？
Hey, what are you doing?!
然后，我们就只管混到车流当中…
Then all we do is blend in with traffic...
…不要引起人们的注意
...without arousing suspicion.
一旦到了机场 就没人能阻挡咱们了
Once at the airport, there's no stopping us.
停下！安检
Stop! Security.
- 你和你的小昆虫还有你的彩车？ - 是的
- You and your insect pack your float? - Yes.
- 它一直都是归你所有吗？ - 是的
Has it been in your possession the entire time?
你愿意脱下鞋，拿出包里的所有东西吗？
Would you remove your shoes?
- 你能脱下你的蜂刺不？ - 啊，那可是我身体的一部分
- Remove your stinger. - It's part of me.
我知道，只是开个小玩笑，旅途愉快
I know. Just having some fun. Enjoy your flight.
接下来，如果我们够幸运的话 我们应该有足够的花粉
Then if we're lucky, we'll have just enough pollen to do the job.
你能想像我们有多幸运吗？ 我们有的花粉刚好够用！
Can you believe how lucky we are? We have just enough pollen to do the job!
我猜这个能管用 （重新授粉：可行）
I think this is gonna work.
必须得管用
It's got to work.
乘客们，请注意，我是机长斯科特
Attention, passengers, this is Captain Scott.
我们得到消息：纽约天气有变
We have a bit of bad weather in New York.
看起来我们得推迟几个小时行程了
It looks like we'll experience a couple hours delay.
巴里，这些剪下来的花儿水分不多 再拖延就用不了了
Barry, these are cut flowers with no water. They'll never make it.
我得去驾驶室跟他们说说
I gotta get up there and talk to them.
小心点
Be careful.
可以帮我看下这本《天幕》杂志吗？
Can I get help with the Sky Mall magazine?
我想要订购会说话的充气鼻子还有耳鬓修剪器
I'd like to order the talking inflatable nose and ear hair trimmer.
机长，我是真的遇到麻烦了
Captain, I'm in a real situation.
- 你刚才说什么，嗯？ - 我什么都没说
- What'd you say, Hal? - Nothing.
有蜜蜂！
Bee!
别紧张！我们整个种族…
Don't freak out! My entire species...
你到底在干嘛？
What are you doing?
- 等一下，我是来洽谈的 - 谁来洽谈？
- Wait a minute! I'm an attorney! - Who's an attorney?
别动
Don't move.
（紧急救生筏）
你都干了些什么啊，巴里
Oh, Barry.
下午好，乘客们，我是你们的机长
Good afternoon, passengers. This is your captain.
有位叫维纳莎・布鲁姆的小姐，座位号为24B 可以过来驾驶室一趟吗？
Would a Miss Vanessa Bloome in 24B please report to the cockpit?
请马上过来！
And please hurry!
这里怎么了？
What happened here?
我试着跟他们沟通，可是那有个吸尘器 还有假发，最后弹出个充气救生艇来
There was a DustBuster, a toupee, a life raft exploded.
一个是秃顶，一个进了船，两个都不省人事了
One's bald, one's in a boat, they're both unconscious!
- 这又是一个蜜蜂笑话？ - 不是！
- Is that another bee joke? - No!
没人驾驶飞机了！
No one's flying the plane!
这里是JFK机场控制中心，356号航班 请汇报你现在的情况
This is JFK control tower, Flight 356. What's your status?
我是维纳莎・布鲁姆，来自纽约的养花人
This is Vanessa Bloome. I'm a florist from New York.
怎么不见飞行员？
Where's the pilot?
他昏倒了，还有副驾驶也一样
He's unconscious, and so is the copilot.
不太妙，机上有人有飞行经验吗？
Not good. Does anyone onboard have flight experience?
事实上，确有一位
As a matter of fact, there is.
- 这位是谁？ - 巴里・班森
- Who's that? - Barry Benson.
就是蜜蜂大审判的那位？！噢，好极了
From the honey trial?! Oh, great.
维纳莎，这个只不过是只超大金属蜂
Vanessa, this is nothing more than a big metal bee.
它有一对大翅膀，大的引擎
It's got giant wings, huge engines.
我不会开飞机
I can't fly a plane.
- 为什么不行？约翰・特拉沃尔塔也不是飞行员吧？ - 对
- Why not? Isn't John Travolta a pilot? - Yes.
那它能有多难？
How hard could it be?
等等，巴里！我们正飞向一堆闪电
Wait, Barry! We're headed into some lightning.
这里是鲍勃・班布 我们收到最新消息，来自JFK机场
This is Bob Bumble. We have some late-breaking news from JFK Airport,
扣人心弦的一幕正在上演
where a suspenseful scene is developing.
巴里・班森，成名于他的诉讼胜利…
Barry Benson, fresh from his legal victory...
那是巴里！
That's Barry!
…他正努力让一驾飞机着陆 机上还载着乘客，鲜花
...is attempting to land a plane, loaded with people, flowers
以及失去知觉的乘务人员
and an incapacitated flight crew.
鲜花？！
Flowers?!
我们在这个区域遇到了风暴 只有两个人在驾驶飞机
We have a storm in the area and two individuals at the controls
但是根本就没有什么飞行经验
with absolutely no flight experience.
稍等一下，迪奇・沃特先生 有一只蜜蜂在那驾飞机上
Just a minute. There's a bee on that plane.
我相当了解班森先生，以及他的所作所为 还有他那指望不上的伙伴
I'm quite familiar with Mr. Benson and his no-account compadres.
他们已经把这儿毁的差不多了
They've done enough damage.
但现在他不是你唯一的希望吗？
But isn't he your only hope?
拜托，蜜蜂根本就不该飞起来的
Technically, a bee shouldn't be able to fly at all.
它们的翅膀太小…
Their wings are too small...
喂，等一下，这话我们不是听了上千遍了吗？
Haven't we heard this a million times?
“翅膀表面积与身体质量不成比例云云”
"The surface area of the wings and body mass make no sense."
- 把这条线直播出去！ - 没问题
- Get this on the air! - Got it.
- 各就各位 - 我们上直播了
- Stand by. - We're going live.
我们工作的方法对你来说可能比较神秘
The way we work may be a mystery to you.
制作蜂蜜要动用大量的蜜蜂 要做大量的细节工作
Making honey takes a lot of bees doing a lot of small jobs.
但是让我来跟你讲讲什么是细节工作
But let me tell you about a small job.
如果你做的好的话 结果将是大不同
If you do it well, it makes a big difference.
远非我们所想 对于我们，对于每个人
More than we realized. To us, to everyone.
这就是为什么我想让蜜蜂们重新开始工作
That's why I want to get bees back to working together.
那才是蜜蜂的生活方式！我们可不是果冻做的
That's the bee way! We're not made of Jell-O.
我们要做别人的坚强后盾
We get behind a fellow.
- 黑与黄！ - 在！
- Black and yellow! - Hello!
左，右，下，盘旋
Left, right, down, hover.
- 盘旋？ - 忽略盘旋
- Hover? - Forget hover.
你知道吗，这没那么难嘛 嘀-嘀！嘀-嘀！
This isn't so hard. Beep-beep! Beep-beep!
巴里，发生什么了？
Barry, what happened?!
等等，我想我们一直处于自动驾驶状态 （自动驾驶：关闭）
Wait, I think we were on autopilot the whole time.
- 那可能是帮到了我们 - 不过现在却不是了！
- That may have been helping me. - And now we're not!
那就是说，我还是不会开飞机
So it turns out I cannot fly a plane.
（警戒等级从“一些蜂”上升为“所有蜂”） 全体都有了，让我们来做他的后盾吧！出发！
All of you, let's get behind this fellow! Move it out!
出发！
Move out!
咱们唯一的机会就是我依靠本能反应 你就照搬我的动作到飞机两翼上
Our only chance is if I do what I'd do, you copy me with the wings of the plane!
你用不着大声嚷嚷
Don't have to yell.
我没有嚷嚷，咱们可是一直都处在大麻烦中
I'm not yelling! We're in a lot of trouble.
我很难集中精神，都怪你那恐慌的语调！
It's very hard to concentrate with that panicky tone in your voice!
这不是什么语调，我是在惊吼！
It's not a tone. I'm panicking!
我想我做不来着这个！
I can't do this!
维纳莎，你要集中精神，听我说 你必须得振作起来！
Vanessa, pull yourself together. You have to snap out of it!
你才要振作起来
You snap out of it.
- 你才要振作起来 - 你才要振作起来
- You snap out of it! - You snap out of it!
- 等一下！ - 怎么了？来啊，到我打了
- Hold it! - Why? Come on, it's my turn.
怎么这飞机飞起来了？
How is the plane flying?
我不知道
I don't know.
喂？
Hello?
班森，在里面玩的时候有没有鲜花啊？
Benson, got any flowers for a happy occasion in there?
授粉大队！
The Pollen Jocks!
他们确实成了某人的后盾
They do get behind a fellow.
- 黑与黄嘛 - 喂
- Black and yellow. - Hello.
好了，让咱们来把这个铁罐子降落到柏油路上
All right, let's drop this tin can on the blacktop.
什么柏油路？哪里？ 我什么也看不见，你能吗？
Where? I can't see anything. Can you?
不，什么都没有，全是云彩
No, nothing. It's all cloudy.
加油，巴里，我们是蜜蜂
Come on. You got to think bee, Barry.
- 我们是蜜蜂 - 我们是蜜蜂
- Thinking bee. - Thinking bee.
我们是蜜蜂！我们是蜜蜂！我们是蜜蜂！
Thinking bee! Thinking bee! Thinking bee!
等一下，我想我感觉到了什么
Wait a minute. I think I'm feeling something.
- 什么？ - 不知道，但是很强烈，引导着我
- What? - I don't know. It's strong, pulling me.
仿佛是2700万年沉淀下的本能
Like a 27-million-year-old instinct.
把机头向下降低
Bring the nose down.
我们是蜜蜂！我们是蜜蜂！我们是蜜蜂！
Thinking bee! Thinking bee! Thinking bee!
- 什么东西跑到停机场上去了？ - 把灯光调过去！
- What in the world is on the tarmac? - Get some lights on that!
我们是蜜蜂！我们是蜜蜂！我们是蜜蜂！
Thinking bee! Thinking bee! Thinking bee!
- 维纳莎，对准鲜花 - 好的
- Vanessa, aim for the flower. - OK.
- 关掉引擎！ - 关掉引擎？ - 咱们现在要启动蜂力马达了，准备好了么伙计们？
Cut the engines. We're going in on bee power. Ready, boys?
已经待命！
Affirmative!
很好，很好，别急，就这样
Good. Good. Easy, now. That's it.
降在那朵鲜花上
Land on that flower!
准备好了？全速倒档！
Ready? Full reverse!
向后转！
Spin it around!
- 不是那朵花！是另一朵！ - 到底哪朵？
- Not that flower! The other one! - Which one?
- 那朵花 - 我正开向那朵花呢！
- That flower. - I'm aiming at the flower!
那是个肥仔穿着花花衬衫 我是指那个巨大的闪烁的鲜花
That's a fat guy in a flowered shirt. I mean the giant pulsating flower
组成元素是几百万只蜜蜂！
made of millions of bees!
向前拉伸，机头向下，机尾向上
Pull forward. Nose down. Tail up.
回转过来
Rotate around it.
- 这太疯狂了，巴里！ - 就是唯一我知道的飞行的方法
- This is insane, Barry! - This's the only way I know how to fly.
是我神精错乱了，还是这飞机 以类昆虫模式飞行呢？
Am I koo-koo-kachoo, or is this plane flying in an insect-like pattern?
把机头调到那，别害怕，跟着感觉，全速倒档
Get your nose in there. Don't be afraid. Smell it. Full reverse!
尽管降下它，就像你是它的一部分
Just drop it. Be a part of it.
对准中心
Aim for the center!
现在降下它，降下它，女士！
Now drop it in! Drop it in, woman!
好了，已经到了
Come on, already.
巴里，咱们成功了！你教会了我如何飞翔！
Barry, we did it! You taught me how to fly!
- 是的，别来击掌！ - 对了
- Yes. No high-five! - Right.
巴里，它管用了！你看到那个巨大的鲜花没？
Barry, it worked! Did you see the giant flower?
什么巨大鲜花？在哪？我当然看到 那鲜花了！那可真是杰作，伙计，杰作！
What giant flower? Where? Of course I saw the flower! That was genius!
- 谢谢你 - 不过这事还没完
- Thank you. - But we're not done yet.
听着，蜜蜂们！
Listen, everyone!
这条飞机跑道上覆盖的是最后的花粉了
This runway is covered with the last pollen
它们来自最后的鲜花，地球上再也没有了
from the last flowers available anywhere on Earth.
这是我们最后的机会了
That means this is our last chance.
只有我们蜜蜂才会酿蜜，传花粉，并且穿成这样
We're the only ones who make honey, pollinate flowers and dress like this.
如果我们想延续我们的种族 那现在就行动吧！你们怎么认为？
If we're gonna survive as a species, this is our moment! What do you say?
咱们是要做回蜜蜂，还是要做博物馆里 陈列的生物链标本？
Are we going to be bees, orjust Museum of Natural History keychains?
做蜜蜂！
We're bees!
做标本！
Keychain!
那么跟我来吧！除了那个要做标本的
Then follow me! Except Keychain.
等一下，巴里，看这
Hold on, Barry. Here.
这是你应得的
You've earned this.
耶！
Yeah!
我成了授粉大队的一员！挺合身嘛 就是袖子得改改
I'm a Pollen Jock! And it's a perfect fit. All I gotta do are the sleeves.
噢，耶
Oh, yeah.
那个是我们家的巴里
That's our Barry.
歌曲为披头士乐队1969年名曲《Here Comes The Sun》 此版本由Sheryl Crow翻唱
妈妈！蜜蜂回来了！
Mom! The bees are back!
如果有谁想要给家打个电话，快去打
If anybody needs to make a call, now's the time.
我感觉我们今晚要熬夜了
I got a feeling we'll be working late tonight!
找你零钱，祝你下午愉快 下一位，想买些什么？
Here's your change. Have a great afternoon! Can I help who's next?
你还想再来点儿蜂蜜到吗？ 这是蜜蜂授权的哦，别忘了还有这些 [昆虫 法津咨询]
Would you like some honey with that? It is bee-approved. Don't forget these.
牛奶，奶酪，干酪，都是我的 可是我没看着一个子儿
Milk, cream, cheese, it's all me. And I don't see a nickel!
有时我觉得自己只不过是块牛肉
Sometimes I just feel like a piece of meat!
这些我一点也不知道
I had no idea.
巴里，不好意思，可不可以占用几分钟？
Barry, I'm sorry. Have you got a moment?
请您原谅，我的蚊子助理会帮你的
Would you excuse me? My mosquito associate will help you.
对不起我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
他也是个律师？
He's a lawyer too?
女士，我本来就是吸人血的寄生虫了 我仅需一个公文包（就成律师了）
I was already a blood-sucking parasite. All I needed was a briefcase.
祝您下午愉快！
Have a great afternoon!
巴里，我刚刚收到一份超大郁金香订单 可是我怎么也弄不到货
Barry, I just got this huge tulip order, and I can't get them anywhere.
没问题，维尼，交给我就行了
No problem, Vannie. Just leave it to me.
你就是我的救世主，巴里 下一位，需要点儿什么？
You're a lifesaver, Barry. Can I help who's next?
好了，紧急起飞，伙计们，该出去飞飞了
All right, scramble, jocks! It's time to fly.
谢谢你，巴里！
Thank you, Barry!
噢！那只蜜蜂抢走了我的生活！
That bee is living my life!
顺其自然吧，肯尼 （店招：维纳莎与巴里 鲜花 蜂蜜 法律咨询）
Let it go, Kenny.
- 几时这噩梦才能结束？！ - 顺其自然吧
- When will this nightmare end?! - Let it all go.
- 好天气正适合飞行 - 正是
- Beautiful day to fly. - Sure is.
告诉你个秘密，我早就想离开那个办公室了
Between you and me, I was dying to get out of that office.
（不要着急关闭，演职员表最后还有几句台词^^）
TLF中文字幕站 http://tlfsubs.eastgame.net
伙计，你得时刻想着：我们是蜜蜂
You have got to start thinking bee, my friend.
- 我们是蜜蜂！ - 说我呢？ （后面还有台词^^）
- Thinking bee! - Me?
等一下，给我点儿时间，等一下
Hold it. Let's just stop for a second. Hold it.
对不起，对不起，对不起大家了 可以就在这儿停一下吗？
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, everyone. Can we stop here?
我不会在谢幕表演中做出生命中的重要决定！
I'm not making a major life decision during a production number!
好了好了，休息十分钟，所有人都有了 马上闭幕，伙计们
All right. Take ten, everybody. Wrap it up, guys.
我实际上没排练过这段
I had virtually no rehearsal for that.